== 字幕制作：掌上电脑 根据 Vobsub 转换 SRT ==
“街景”阿佛列纽曼作曲指挥
二十世纪福斯交响乐团演奏
贝蒂嘉宝、玛丽莲梦露
罗伦巴克尔
愿嫁金龟婿
编剧：努那尼强生
制作：努那尼强生
导演：珍纳古列斯柯
纽约，一个美妙的地方
纽约，纽约！一个忙碌、目眩
混乱，令人震惊的地方
带着大把钞票的男人
试图把它花掉
拥有内在才能的美人
努力想表现它
搭乘计程车或地下铁到百老汇
到了市中心
那个如旋转木马的纽约
有百万富翁和灰姑娘
相约在史托克
中央公园
浪漫的宝贝和朋友们
相约在黑夜中
疯狂的城市，尖塔戴着帽子
嘈杂的城市，有数百万的人
通往荣光、财富与名声之门
你将永远无法满足
千万别忘了它的悸动
光荣的、动人的奇幻世界
纽约！
班顿先生到了吗
我是地产经纪
是的，小姐
他已经到了，正在等您
谢谢
早安，佩姬太太
希望没让你久等了
我也才刚来
恐怕你会有点失望
你见不到屋主丹马克先生
他今天早上飞到欧洲去了
天啊，我真的很失望
那真是太突然了
是啊
但你也知道要是你逃了一年税
税务局的人会怎么盯着你
当然
现在你想租久一点也可以
不介意的话，麻烦你把门打开
当然没问题
租约要签多久呢
多久都没关系
但他坚持租金是一个月一千元
所以我才会想跟他见面
他应该这几年都不会住在这里
听说威斯克先生真的有麻烦了
你是说他不会回来了
有可能
我知道他真的干下蠢事
我明白了
那么情况也就不同了
租约在哪里
对不起，我没把租约带出来
没关系，你可以寄过来
这是两个月的房租
第一个月跟最后一个月
那么说我们成交了？
没错
你什么时候开始住？
可以现在就住进来吗？
当然可以
虽然有点不寻常，但是…
谢谢，班顿先生，你真好人
谢谢，佩姬太太
很高兴跟这样果断的女人
做生意
我们做地产经纪的…
再见
对，当然
差点忘了，你租约要签多久?
一年应该就够了，谢谢
但你不觉得你应该…
喂
成功了
我马上过去
请往左走
谢谢
把眼镜戴上，这里还没有男人
你来得真快，搭的士来的吗？
不，我没钱搭的士
又是那开名贵房车的人送我来
是那部有黄金装饰的车吗
是黄金的吗？
那人坐在我旁，我不想戴眼镜
那人开的是有黄金装饰的车
天啊
很棒吧
好漂亮
我们真的能搬进来吗？
我要打电话给萝可
哪个萝可？
我跟你说过
那来自泽西的女孩
你还记得吧
你没跟我说过她叫萝可
她不是叫萝可
只是其他模特儿都这么叫她
意思说她很疯狂
我也那么认为
成功了，你给我等一下
等一下，萝可
我不能跟陌生人住在一起
而且她还很疯狂
如果你不愿意的话也没关系
我只是要请她来这里
如果你喜欢的话，那就算了
她的品味高吗？
没错
我没告诉过你
她上过三次时装杂志吗？
她知道怎么处理状况吗？
这点我们就得走着瞧了
萝可
甚么？
你有多少钱？
两毫五仙
太棒
你立刻来，帮我们买午餐
有多少人？
三个人
好吧，我买了东西就赶来
那对百万富翁来说真是大诱惑
她只有两毫五仙
或许吧
但她会把那笔钱处理得很好
我真的不知道该怎样谢谢你
我实在是太丢脸了
是的，别客气
任何人都可能会忘了带钱的
我知道
嗨，甜心
快进来
进来吧
谢谢
我在快餐店遇到这位先生
你说你叫甚么名字呢？
汤布鲁文
BRooLMAN，布鲁文
这是我的朋友宝娜迪比斯
您好
这是佩姬小姐，对吧？
是佩姬太太
您好，这真的是太有趣了
我当时在点烟牛肉和薯仔沙律
听到狄比西小姐跟柜台解释
她只有两毫五…
你可省省力气，我们会问她
要我把东西放到厨房去吗？
不必了，我想还是不要
厨师她还没穿衣服
真的吗？
非常谢谢，我想或许…
若你不介意的话，改天再说吧
你何不下星期再打电话来呢？
但我不知道你们的电话号码
没关系，电话簿里有
真是谢谢你，布鲁文先生
但我不知道你叫甚么啊？
他的为人真是很好
我还以为他会跟我们一起午餐
听着，这次行动的第一条规则
是来访的男士必须打领带
我不想无礼
如果我们跟那样的人来往
我们可能会立刻就会被丢出去
谢谢你，力克，零钱你留着吧
您好，布鲁文先生
嗨，彼得
布鲁文大楼
接下来你们得记住
你们在快餐店里遇到的人
是比不上住在豪华大厦里的人
但他很可爱
你不那么认为吗？
他当然很可爱
但我认识的那些
油站工人都可爱
他是加油站工人吗？
我敢打赌他一定是的
我了解这些男人
我曾嫁给这样的男人
他们非常可爱
我不知道你结过婚
她刚刚从雷诺回来
那么你一定很有钱了
不，我是闪电离婚的
那个家伙结了两次婚
但那是违法的，不是吗
我为那个男人疯狂
你知道他是怎么对待我的吗？
首先他的名字是假的
结果我发现他已经结婚了
第三，从牧师说完阿门后
他就什么事都不做
接下来我只知道
他偷了我的电视机卖给车厂
当我质问他时
他把我打个半死
打得半死？
不，他把我剥光了毒打
我觉得他好坏啊
我最后一次看到他时
我在油站下车一会儿
结果却得自己走路回家
我很讶异你会想要再婚
那就是这次计划的重点
我当然想再婚
谁不想呢？
那可是人生大事
但大部份人对婚姻草草了事
她们在赛马时
挑撰马匹花的时间
比选丈夫时还多
真的吗？
所以你得用脑
而不是感情用事
我明白了
告诉她，你对这间公寓的计划
简单来说，我的计划是这样的
如果你得在世上挑一个男人
你要嫁给有钱人还是穷人？
我想我要嫁给有钱人
好吧，哪较有可能
遇到有钱人？
在阿姆斯特丹街的破公寓
还是像这样的豪宅里呢？
应该是像这样的豪宅里吧
好吧，那就对了
我们都得努力
我们得尽力把自己
打扮得漂亮点
把结婚计划弄好
高尚的穿着，高尚的背景
有品味的个性
你们千万别忘了
年薪没有六位数子的男人
就不行
我这辈子没听过这样
聪明的计划
工欲善其事，必先利其器
好吧，我们把陷阱设好了
现在有人把熊给敲昏就行了
你是说嫁给他吗？
如果你不想嫁他
你就抓不住他，是他抓住你
我从小开始就抱有一个梦想
我想嫁给百万富翁
你知道我想嫁给谁吗？
谁？
洛克菲勒
哪个洛克菲勒？
我不在乎
我不介意嫁给凡登比特
或是凯迪拉克先生
没有凯迪拉克先生，我查过了
有达斯柯先生吗？
没有
有钱的印度大君可以吗？
有三个吗？
如果我们跟他们共进晚餐
而他们娶了我们，那真捧
想想那些钻石跟红宝石
还有那些疯狂的大象
那真的是太棒了，对吧？
生活方式跟我们不一样的人
都非常的疯狂
不知道谁要付钱啊？
对，钱该怎么办呢？
我来告诉你们吧
我就知道好日子过不了多久
放轻松点，好吗？
再去开一瓶吧
晚安
我是班特音乐公司的班特
您是…
没错，请进
谢谢
我打电话给你是要问你
愿意付多少钱买这架钢琴
这架钢琴非常漂亮
真的，宝娜
我想她是我见过最聪明的人
你明白的，它状况不是很好
但我们可以付你两千五
成交
孩子们
我们今晚去哪里吃饭？
史托克俱乐部
还是二十一餐厅呢
喂
是塔拉菲嘉75098吗？
是的
您是哪位？佩姬太太吗？
对，您是哪位？
我是汤布鲁文
你记得我
当然，但是…
我一直在想你
但我今早看到一本旧杂志后
才知道你是谁
你是甚么意思？
你是去无的史坦巴克啤酒小姐
对，我相信我是
你在杂志里广告里
一直在一条带子旁边跳跃
我不是在跳跃，我是在跳舞
所以我才打电话给你
不知道你愿意跟我一起
晚餐吗？
哪天都行
今晚可以吗？
恐怕今晚不行
明晚呢？
对不起
那星期四晚上呢？
听住，布鲁文先生
你打电话给我是在浪费时间
别再打来了，好吗？
嗨，小姑娘
宝娜
甚么事？
你认为我们会成功吗？
你是甚么意思？
过了快三个月了
我们连订婚都没有
更别说结婚
如果我要的话
上星期便可订婚
你跟谁订婚？
那个英国人
甚么英国人？
就是跟我借五元的那个高个子
那就是我想说的事
我们那么认真的想结婚
结果得到了什么？
你钓到一个穷光蛋
他还跟你借了五元
我被约去汉堡天堂吃晚餐
萝可每晚跟便利店
识的男人出去
他送他五顶浴帽
三盒阿士匹灵
你觉得我们会有什么下场呢？
我觉得问题不是我
应该是现在的男人有问题
他们越来越紧张
特别是有钱人
我们下星期要坐在哪里呢？
我们两个都努力过了
想立刻查出
男人有多少钱是不易
或是他们是否结婚了
那看起来像是在打听
他们的私隐
如果不快想个办法
我们会被踢到马路上去
我们只需要逮到一次机会
那就是设陷阱的美妙之处
你不必抓到一群男人
只要逮到一只大肥羊就行了
或许是萝可拿着免费纸巾
回来了
谢谢
嗨，夏兹
嗨
这位是…
对不起
你刚说你叫什么名字？
我是J.D.汉利
当然，这位是夏兹佩姬
这位是宝娜迪比斯
您好
两位女士，您们好
我在伯格多夫的店
遇到汉利先生
真的吗？
对，那里的店员很好
你得原谅我们家里空荡荡
我们家具送去干洗了
若你不介意，请到饭厅来
我当然不介意
今天我们的女佣放假了
所以无法好好招待您
请坐吧
谢谢，但我不能久待
我只是帮狄比西小姐
拿东西上来
汉利先生来自德州的达拉斯
真的吗？
您是做石油那一行吗？
我只投资了一小部份在石油
大部份还是在牧场上
是股票跟债券吗？
不，我不投资那种东西
我是指那些白脸长角的畜性
你是说？
我养牛只
我知道了，你是养牛的
我明了
你真的不多坐一会吗？
我现在没空
但我跟狄比西小姐提过了
我是石油机构小组织的会员
那里的会员都是无长的生意人
我们今晚要开正式的欢迎会
我很荣幸地邀请你们
我相信这会让我们很快乐
你说那里的人
都从事石油买卖？
事实上，有些人可能是银行家
银行家很棒，你觉得呢？
没错
我知道这有点突然跟不方便
但我们可跳舞喝酒，好好玩下
我觉得听起来很棒
我喜欢好好地玩一玩
那就这么说定了
我很乐意
太棒了
若不介意
我约八点半来接你们
我们会见到其他男人吗？
你会见到全部的人
别担心，他们不像我那么老
你到底在说什么？
少胡说了，你并不老
我觉得你很无轻
各位女士，谢谢你们
你们让我这次纽约之旅
变得很有价值
再见
我想机会来了，小姑娘
在那个大房间里
只有我们跟百万富翁
那可是1947年的事
我觉得那是个好主意
我们要去哪里？
有一家新开的店
晚安，女士
我是汉利，有二人位吗？
当然有，先生
这边请，女士
要喝香槟吗？
好的
有二人位吗？菲利普
当然有，女士，这边请
我们要最好的位置
当然，先生
这是我们最好的位置
一支香槟
哪一种香槟呢？
我要最好的
没问题，先生
晚安
晚安，二人位
这边请
这边，亲爱的
对不起
你说你是独自一人来这里？
不，是跟很多德州人一起来
全都是男人吗？
有些人带了太太
你今晚也遇到了一些
其他人的太太都去看表演了
你知道女人到了纽约会做什么
我知道
我想艾拉过去三年来
看了五次表演了
我明日了
艾拉是我女儿
真的吗？
麦斯太太也跟你一起来吗？
没有麦斯太太，我住在纽约
我说得够清楚了吗？
非常清楚
你结婚了吗？
结婚？
有时我觉得我是美国
最具已婚身份的男人
你知道我今晚来这里时
我家里有多少女人吗？
我不知道
七个
我太太
她那个离婚的姐姐
我一点都不怪她丈夫
她们那个看起来
有一百一十岁的妈妈
还有个来自麻州
北阿特巴的阿姨
还有其他三个阿姨
我连她们的名字都记不住
说真的
直到去年
我才觉当寡人很寂寞
刚开始时孩子们都陪着我
但他们现在长大了
我儿子结婚了，艾拉订婚了
我得承认现在
我家看起来太大太空旷了
我想像得到
所以我最近才会常常旅行
伦敦、南法，卡皮瑞等地
但真的一点都不好玩
我了解，真的不好玩
几年前，我租了一艘船
虽然不大，但很舒服
我花了六个月时间环游世界
但一点用都没有
我想只有一个办法能治疗寂寞
是甚么？
有人陪伴
你说得对
你说得再对不过了
我不习惯跟已婚男人出席场合
如果我在派对上先问过你
我就不会跟你来这里了
这是没有错的，对吧？
如果这真的是没有错
我是第一次遇到这种事
我第一个反应当然是
直接亲自到阿拉伯一趟
仔细地了解状况
我确定来自苏可尼跟新泽西
标准石油的人都到了
毕竟那可是一笔大生意
大概有两、三亿吧
很自然我绝不会冒险
没错
问题是我从那个在油站
工作的男人身上学到了教训
我从没遇过那种人
所以我一点戒心都没有
这家伙是帮标准石油工作
你该不会是他的老板吧
不，不是
标准石油的老板是洛克菲勒
他是你的朋友吗？
恐怕不是的
但正如我所说…
如果你住在那种疯人院里
你会常常出城去的
你明白我的意思吗？
我明白
但我现在想出办法来了
我在缅因州买了一楝小木屋
我喜欢小木屋
是吗？
我简直是爱死了
你是说…
你愿意去看看我的小木屋吗？
我非常愿意
因为如果你想去的话
我星期五下午会去
我爱死它们了
化妆室
如果你想知道我钓到什么男人
我只能说我是个很快乐的女人
汉利先生不只是个完美的男人
他还很体贴呢
你不觉得他有点老吗？
成熟点，好吗？
有钱的男人永远都不老
我的男伴也很有钱
但他真的很无聊
对，我觉得他应该不是单身
他不是
你为何要在他身上浪费时间？
不然我能找谁呢？
除非你要我甩掉他
加入你跟你的朋友
你那么做的话
我会在全餐厅的人前
扭断你脖子
而且他邀请我参加盛大的派对
是吗？什么时候？
我们星期五下午出发
出发到哪里？
他在缅因州的小木屋
你疯了吗？
我想不是，我喜欢小木屋
你不能去
那违反我们的计划，你知道的
为什么我不能去？
我可能会在那遇到别人
对吧？
你会在缅因州遇到什么人？
爱斯基摩人吗？
你们看到我的男伴了吗？
我看到了
他长什么样子？
他是个很帅的独眼龙
就那样
你觉得他为何戴上眼罩？
我不知道那是眼罩
我还以为有人把他打成黑眼圈
真的，宝娜
你为何不戴上眼镜
看看你的男伴长什么样子呢？
不，我不会冒那种险的
你知大家怎么说
戴眼镜的女孩？
或许有人开枪
把他的眼睛打瞎了
他听起来是个好人
但我很好奇地想知道他的长相
他是谁啊？
我不知道
但他提到的东西
没有一项是低于一百万的
我的男伴很有格调
他从没提他的财富
他只是把富有表现了出来
布威斯特先生说
他的家庭很糟糕
但我得为他声明
我们点的东西，全超过了五元
如果你们有吃剩的东西
别忘了告诉服务生
你要包起来带回家给狗吃
我们最好快回去吧
免得他们的热情冷却了
缅因州到底在哪里？
我要那个…
结帐吧
是的，汉利太太
下一站阿拉伯
您好，我的朋友
您好，大人
您好
这些是送给我朋友的太太的
这不过是我送您的一份薄礼
他在开玩笑吗？
不是
这是东方欢迎客人的习俗
麻烦你帮我告诉他
我觉得这很棒
嗨，时装店吗？
布鲁文先生想跟安东先生说话
谢谢
安东先生吗？
您的电话
是东尼吗？
对
嗨，您好
您好吗？布鲁文先生
我很好
告诉我，德州的衣服挑得如何
就是沙滩装跟其他的衣服？
你是说那些特级的服装吗?
对，我有个阿姨想买些衣服
她几岁了？
约二十五岁，她是我小阿姨
我可以帮你介绍一下
我可以看看吗？
今天可以吗？
很好，我有个点子
东尼，你认识一个
叫做夏兹的模特儿吗？
谁？
夏兹
您是说佩姬太太吧
没错
你的店挺漂亮的
谢谢您的夸奖，先生
麻烦您坐这里
对不起
您阿姨是金发或皮肤微黑呢？
这要视天气而定
我处理的方式是
我要跟汉利先生速战速决
你要怎么办？
像母亲一样地照顾他？
不，那对小伙子来说很管用
但汉利先生想要的
不是一个母亲
第一套衣服叫做湿地的彩虹
粉蓝色的透明丝制日装
有着宽大的裙子
很适合参加鸡尾酒会
和午后约会
当然了
钻石是女人的最好朋友
我们在此证明了这一点
你不会真的
要跟那个笨蛋去吧？
天啊，当然不
轮到你了，萝可
天啊
我们叫这套衣服为「看看我」
这是一套观赏体育运动的服装
你好
嗨
可以拿来做一件式的服装
它是用很好的羊毛材料做成的
接下来的衣服叫
「午安，甜心」
这是一套下午茶服装
它的后面比前面出色
是由进□的纱所制成
还搭配了很漂亮的洋伞
你喜欢吗？先生
很不错
那家伙终于露出马脚了
我还是觉得他很可爱
他是谁？
那个工人
什么工人？
我在快餐店遇到的那个男人
午后的麻烦
粉红色跟白色条纹的水手装
配上深玫瑰的宽腰带
「狠心的汉娜」是一件散步装
配上了芥辣色的裤子
灰白色的丝制上衣
接下来是双冻鸡尾酒
这沙滩装有羊毛制的
蓝色柔软裤
还有漂亮的丝上衣
你会注意到它搭配的帽子
极具埃及风味
「国境之南」采用
墨西哥黑丝棉条纹质料
有着色彩活泼的披肩跟草帽
我能再看那件蓝色
跟粉红色吗？
当然可以，先生
夏兹小姐
谢谢你，东尼
别客气，先生
你有看到中意的衣服吗？
不，我没看到我要的东西
再次谢谢你，东尼
好了，女孩们，谢谢
东尼先生
什么事？
我认识那家伙，他是个骗子
骗子？
他是在骗你
夏兹小姐
什么事？
我有教你如何绑腰带吗？
从来都没有
那你最好别告诉我如何做生意
您是布威斯特先生吗？
是的
我来拿
车要开了
平时司机不是你，对吧？
是的，平时的司机是我爸爸
但他昨晚去参加国民大会
他今天早上起不来
那个地方一定很有趣
甚么地方很有趣？
大会
这是甚么？
当然是小木屋了
这间房子？
生了火后，看起来会较舒服
但其他人在哪里？
什么其他人？
游客
对不起，狄比西小姐
我真的不知道你在说什么
什么游客？
你说过这是一间小木屋
对吧？
一点都没错
那么其他的游客在哪里？
像是大角鹿小木屋游乐场
妈妈跟我两年前到宾州的
大角鹿小木屋游乐场去
那里有很多游客
那是我一生中
最快乐的时光之一
你以为这里跟那里一样
当然了
这些行李要放哪里？
把它们提回车上
怎么了？发生了什么事？
我们现在要回纽约
今天恐怕是没办法了
要到明天才有火车
我好想死
要生火吗？
对，我正要生火
没关系，我来吧
我一辈子从没看过这么多雪
对不起，狄比西小姐
请忍耐一下
我会尽快带你离开
我知道我可能会滑雪
但我没想到会有这么多雪
我在储藏室里放了一些酒
我去帮你倒一杯酒
或许你想听点音乐
或许我想喝点毒药
这里有收音机？
当然，收音机跟房子
什么都有
拿去吧
或许你第一杯最好喝纯的
你听听那首歌
我们老远从纽约赶来
哈利詹姆士真的是太棒了
真的吗？你怎么知道？
我怎么知道那是哈利詹姆士？
因为他是哈利詹姆士
各队先生女士
您正在收听奇奇可兰波的音乐
我们从洛杉几的水晶厅做直播
叫那个骗子闭嘴
你别像一个被宠坏的孩子
乖一点好吗？
我从没遇过这种事
只要我的心智还清楚
我是不会再犯这种错误的
但我们站在这里吵架
对大家来说都没有好处
我觉得好难过，我耳朵好痛
我一点都不难过
喝掉吧
这是兰姆酒吗？
那是梅德福特兰姆酒
存放的年份超过一百年了
那么我是病了，我在发烧
立刻请医生来
你在说什么？
我说我发烧了
只要兰姆酒的味道
跟康乃馨一样
我就是发烧了
我们得立刻请医生来
听着，你不必这么歇斯底里
不要打我
我不会打你的
我只是要摸摸你的额头
门外有温度计
快去拿来
你快叫医生来，我知我发烧了
你只是觉得有点热
你要不要叫医生来？
我不能叫医生来
这里每个人都认识我
你不明白吗？
那我该怎么做呢？
因你在这是名人
我就该死掉吗
温度计有点大，但是…
这附近有医院吗？
把嘴巴张开
那是什么？
把嘴巴张开，我要帮你量体温
我不要用那根笛子来量体温
这不是笛子
这是温度计，你看
但这不是给人量体温的
那是拿来量气温的
我叫你把嘴巴张开
在我把温度计拿出前
不要说话
如果她是我女儿
你知道我会怎么做吗？
她不是你女儿
她也不是我女儿
所以我才会发疯的
几度？
一百零二度
那很糟糕吗？
你只是体温高了一点而已
或许纽约人是那么认为
但在缅因州
她该躺床好好休息
我要死掉了，我知道
我要死在这个蛮荒之地
若你愿意，我可打电话给妈妈
她是个护士
她能帮上什么忙？
我们可以把症状告诉她
她会告诉我们该怎么办的
好吧，但跟她说话时小心点
我只告诉她，你要我说的事
海兹吗？我是伊班
麻烦你叫妈妈来好吗
我在布威斯特的小木屋里
对，他跟他的滑雪板在这里
若我是腮腺炎，我会死掉的
妈妈？若有个女孩一直在发抖
而且发烧到一百零二度
那是怎么一回事呢？
她会流眼泪吗？
她的眼睛跟水龙头一样
她会流眼泪
看看她的舌头
看起来红红的
她的舌头红红的
看看她耳朵后面
你抓过耳朵后面吗？
当然没有
模特儿是不能抓痒的
耳朵后面有破皮
我明白了
好的，谢谢你，妈妈
没什么好担心的
对，但到底怎么了？
她在出麻疹
出麻疹？
我没什么好担心的
妈妈说让她躺到床上休息
要她保持安静
屋子光线要暗的
那可以避免并发症
她一两个星期就会好
零钱留着吧
谢谢
是的，先生
您好吗？麦克
天啊，你好吗？丹麦先生
我还以为你去欧洲了
没错，但我回来了
你是我朋友，对吧？
没错，先生
我跟税务局之间有点误会
我需要你帮忙
没问题，先生
那些人也常找我麻烦
对，现在谁住在我家里？
是三位小姐
我想她们是职业妇女吧
对，我得进去一下
你可以安排一下吗？
你现在可以进去
她们晚上都出去了
一个跟德州人出去了
一个跟独眼龙出去
那另一个呢？
她说要去大角鹿小木屋
你要我在这里等吗？
是的，如果可以的话
若有人按门铃，我会告诉你
那不是她们，她们两三点才回
我马上回来
好吧，我能把灯打开吗？
一定是宝娜没关灯
你要喝点什么？
如果你不介意的话，牛奶就好
牛奶？
我来看看有没有
麻烦你到厨房去好吗？
我马上来
这是我们最棒的饮料吗？
很明显地，是的
但这是我要的
夏兹，你让我这趟旅行很愉快
我想要跟你致谢
别傻了，JD
告诉我
你们的家具
真是拿去干洗了吗？
或是你可提出其他的解释？
你不必担心那个
你把它门卖了还是当了？
是卖了
他们会把家具卖回给你吗？
好了，亲爱的夏兹
恐怕我们得说再见了
再见？
我还以为你要待到下星期呢
本来是的
但发生了我意想不到的事
我觉得马上离开这是最明智了
你是什么意思？
你还记得第一次
我跟萝可来这里的情形吗？
记得
我来到这里时
是个富有的老寡人
我的下半辈子
都打算好要怎过了
真的吗？
但那不是我要离开这里的原因
是吗？
告诉我，你相信一见锺情吗？
当然了，JD
我从来都没怀疑过
但我不相信
到我这年纪是不信
你别再提你的年纪了，好吗？
你以为你是个老头子
你不觉得你正在巅峰期吗？
你几岁了？
四十岁
夏兹
那是你说过最甜美的谎言
你应该是二十五岁，对吧？
听着，JD
你不会妄下结论吧？
听着，这是没有的，亲爱的
我五十六岁了
我比你年轻三十岁
就你的标准来说
我是个老人了
不
在未来的五年中
我们或许还会看不出差异
但当我真的老了时
我们又该怎么办呢？
听着，JD，我讨厌年轻人
非常谢谢您
别客气
你要走了吗？
对恐怕是的
晚安
我想告诉你的是，JD
我一直都喜欢
年纪比较大的男人
看看罗斯福，看看邱吉尔
看看在「非洲女王」里的男主角
我为他们疯狂
你明白了吧，JD
对不起
嗨，请进
希望没打扰了你们
你的确是打扰了我们
别让她吓着你，宝娜
我正要走了
那么早？
对，我明天早上要搭飞机回家
我得走了
再见，亲爱的
很高兴能认识你们
再见，JD，你会回来吧？
或许有一天会吧
再见
你的飞机什么时候起飞？
九点
你不相信我说的话吗？
我相信能娶到你
对我来说是再好不过了
但对你来说那是个悲剧
你在离开前会打电话给我吗？
那对你来说太早了
拜托
好吧
晚安，亲爱的
他是怎么了？
我应该把你的鼻子揍扁
我做了甚么？
没甚么
只是你破坏了我的机会
对不起，夏兹，真的
小迷糊小姐真的很对不起
我只是急着告诉你一个消息
什么消息？
我们要结婚了
你跟谁？
我跟史杜华
你是说独眼龙先生
对，若他这个周末
不必飞到伦敦
他这星期六会带我去见他妈妈
到哪里见他妈妈？
亚特兰大市
你说这家伙是做什么的？
他是石油商，亲爱的
他是卖石油的
那是他说的吧？
当然，你该听听他怎么说的
真的
我想我们最好去查一查
为什么？我不了解你的意思
没妈妈星期六
会待在亚特兰大市
喂
佩姬太太吗？
没错，还是不行
这到底是谁发明的？
发明什么？
在雪地上滑雪？
不然要在什么东西上滑雪？
就像在佛罗里达州那样的
我们在水上滑雪
在水上滑雪？
你…
不要
雪伦太太
她来了
你还好吗？
别管我好不好
你到哪里去了？
我到山上去了
你跟谁去的？
我一个人去的
那是什么？
我要帮你修指甲
他叫什么名字？
伊班
你得小心
你不会跟那种人一起
是吗？
永远都不会
那你觉得我该跟什么人在一起
我的麻疹是会好的
没错，你真的越来越好了
等着我们回纽约去吧
有时我不了解你
你是甚么意思？
你太太是怪物吗？
当然不是，她是个好女人
床上功夫也很厉害
天啊
我是说真的
那你为什么要这样偷食呢？
你说什么？
你那晚在打什么鬼主意？
为了一个理由
你是个漂亮的年轻女人
我知道
还有我那晚心情不好
我女儿跟男人私奔了
我的天啊，那有什么不好呢？
重点是那男人不好
他是个吃软饭的家伙
真的吗？或许我认识他
他叫甚么名字？
他叫马丁尼兹
我听说过他，他是跳舞的
他专钓有钱的女继承人
她不再是了
你是什么意思？
我除去了她的继承权
除去了她的继承权
这一点我就羡慕穷人了
他们不会除去孩子的继承权
很明显的
他们也没甚么好继承
你说什么？
穷人是没有财产
能让后代继承的
那没什么不同
不管我妈多穷
她不会除去我的继承权
你介意我们先别说话吗？
不会啊，我喜欢不说话
我就是要带你来看这个
好漂亮
从第二座山山顶到北边那里
往西边视力所能及的地方
在老巴迪农场后面那边
都是我的
全都是你的
对
你说这些树木跟山
一切都是你的
没错
我的天啊
很漂亮吧
那不是所谓的木材吗？
它们是全世界品质最好的
谁会想得到呢
我觉这里是全世界
最漂亮的地方
我非常赞成
这里纯朴干净，地方又大
你会喜欢这里吗？
我从来没想过这一点
但我想我可以的
你应该在晚上来看看
月光跟星星高挂天际的样子
听着，再跟你说一次
有多少地方是你的
从第二座山山顶到北边那里
往西边视力所能及的地方
这一次没问题
一个去工作，一个去银行
另一个还在大角鹿小木屋
若我记得没错
你上次也是那么说的
我知道，但这次我很肯定
喂
嗨
等一下
她还没回来
是吗？
你要等她吗？
不，谢谢，我得走了
我会告诉她你来过
谢谢
再见
对不起，亲爱的
夏兹的朋友
他过来跟她打招呼
我要告诉你，我希望你怎么做
是的
看来我今晚得到华盛顿吃晚餐
我待会再告诉你
我要跟什么人见面
是的
但那表示我得留在那里过夜
如果你不介意，我要请你
独自搭飞机到亚特兰大市
我会从华盛顿赶过去
跟你在机场会合
你愿意吗？
当然愿意，亲爱的
我帮你安排好行程了
拉关帝亚机场五点有飞机
飞到亚特兰大市
「拉关帝亚机场」
请系上安全带
交给我吧
一切都会没事的
我的天啊
对不起
我们见过吗？
天啊，你是夏兹的朋友
你是怎么了？
你是说什么时候？
昨天
我跟夏兹说你会再来
她一直在等你
我被别的事拖住了
是你太太吗？
我还没结婚
那太好了
听着
什么？
你为什么不戴上眼镜？
什么眼镜？
你不戴眼镜吗？
天啊，不，你为何会那么想
那你是我见过
视力最奇怪的人了
你为什么会那么说？
因为你把书本倒转来看
我没倒转啊
不是你，是书倒转了
那真的很套吧
你怎么了？有散光吗？
不，我的视力跟蝙蝠一样差
我也是
真的吗？
为什么你没戴眼镜？
我戴了啊
没错
我以前也一样
多年来我老是撞上东西
跟雕像握手
那是因为我不想当四眼田鸡
结果发生了一件事
让我永远地改变了我的想法
是甚么事？
有一天晚上
我跟我的三个债主打招呼
但对女孩来说就不一样了
你不那么认为吗？
为什么？
你知道大家怎说
戴眼镜的女孩的
你在说什么？
男人不喜欢戴眼镜的女孩
你试过吗？
你把眼镜带在身上，对吧？
对
你为何不戴上眼镜来试看呢？
拿来做实验？
有何不可呢？
听着，如果你担心我的看法
我在你戴上眼镜前就能告诉你
我真的觉得你是个大美女
真的吗？
真的
我第一次看到你便觉如此
如果你真的那么想的话
快戴上吗
你疯了
不会吧？
你戴上眼镜更美了
没错
让你的脸看起来有点神秘
不会吧
还很特别，有一种独特的感觉
你怎么知道呢？
你已经是个大美女了
希望你不介意我那么说
一点都不会
那种样子的眼镜
让你的脸看起来很特别
你不觉得我戴上它
像老处女吗？
我这辈子从来没看过
这么不像老处女的女人
你叫甚么名字？
事情经过就是这样
我把支票给了这个税务高手
但他没去缴税就算了
他还拿了支票，把钱吞了
为什么你不跟政府说呢？
我说了
但你知道政府是怎么一回事
他们很同情我
但他们还是要我缴钱
在你告诉他们
那家伙是坏蛋后？
那是什么意思？
他们唯一在乎的坏蛋是我
我现在得找出证据
所以我才会想回来拿支票
真的是太棒了
当我发现他逃到肯萨斯时
我立刻跳上飞机
他不把钱拿出
我就扭断他脖子
他在肯萨斯吗？
就我所知是的
那你为什么要去亚特兰大市？
谁要去亚特兰大市？
这架飞机
不是往亚特兰大市吗？
你在说什么？
我们是在往西飞
你在开玩笑吗？
当然不是，再过二十分钟
我们就要降落肯萨斯市了
怎么了？
没什么
只是我想起一件事
继续说吧，再跟我多说一点
把你的一切都告诉我
你的家人跟你住在这里吗？
不，没有
我明了
你是说他们有自己的房子
当然，他们住在迪克斯磨坊
我曾在哈波杂志上
看过一张山间小屋的照片
真的是好漂亮
我们到了
我们到哪里去？
山间小屋，就是这里
你是什么意思？这是山间小屋
当然了，我是怎么告诉你的
但里面很舒服的，来吧
等一下
这是真的吗？
什么是真的？
这里真的是你家吗？
我执勤时住在这里
你以为是怎么样呢？
当然不是这样
我不明白你的意思，甜心
那里是森林了站
但所有的了望站都一样
若你很有钱
你为什么不建大一点的房子？
像哈波杂志上那样的房子
谁很有钱？
你没钱吗？
真的是太好笑了
你为什么会那么想呢?
但你不是说那些树都是你吗?
它们都是我负责看管
那是我工作的一部份
我连灌木丛都没有
但是我以为…
亲爱的，这真是太糟糕了
怎么了？甜心，我不明白
我好爱你
那太棒了，我也很爱你
但是我…
噢，亲爱的
我明了
你对没有树的男人没兴趣
不是这样
我爱你，但是…
如果…
别谈了，好吗?
如果你早告诉我
我跟你说过啊
我们第一次去滑雪时我就说了
我说我是个巡警
那是你的意思吗？
不然我是什么意思
对不起
我以为你是说你来自德州
你爸这次怎么了？
他又去参加共和党大会了
或许他该加入民主党
在缅因州不行，他会很寂寞的
我们在波特兰能租到车吗？
我想可以吧
你是说我们要开车回纽约？
那或许很贵
但我觉那是不被看到的最好办法
你得麻疹时
我不敢冒险外出，免得人看到
但你知道我做了什么吗？
你做了什么？
我打长途电话给芝加哥
跟圣路易的朋友
我要他们帮我签名
发电报给太太
告诉她我临时出差去了
结果非常地成功
那听起来很聪明
我不喜欢自夸
但如果我没有一点小聪明的话
我的家跟事业都会出问题的
你要怎做来表现你的谢意呢？
你是甚么意思？
只要男人出轨成功
他们会做些什么来弥补太太
你不那么认为吗？
譬如说呢？
譬如你明天一早该到卡提尔去
帮你太太买条手镯
买花行吗？
那就是你表达谢意的方式？
你只买五元的天竺葵？
听着，如果我再不是
我太太生日的日子送她珠宝
她十分钟内会请
二十五个私家侦探来盯着我
对不起，我这么老实
但我不敢恭维你的说法
我会送她一盒很漂亮的玫瑰
她一定会喜欢的
听着，她不习惯昂贵的礼物
花之外的礼物都会让她怀疑的
好吧
那你可对你女儿好一点？
什么？
你为什么不恢复她的继承权呢？
对不起，那是不可能的
但在你死掉前
那不会花掉你一分钱的
如果你不介意的话，我不想谈
你到底是怎么了？
大家都会爱自己的孩子
连猴子都是
那是大自然的法则啊
大自然没提到有关小白脸的事
那你还想怎样呢？
应该连你都看得出
这两者的差异
你能跟我说明吗？
如果你不介意的话
我不想跟你争论这个问题
一旦你固执起来
你真的是个大混蛋，对吧？
我们现在在哪里？
我们要越过乔治华盛顿大桥
乔治华盛顿大桥
我们过桥干嘛？
照一般路线走
我会被人认出来
这边没人认识我
那就是利用小聪明
应付这种状况的另一个例子
如果够聪明的话就不需要运气
只要有美国人成功的秘诀
聪明
你什么都不需要
因为事实上当发生问题时
只有人能掌控自己的命运
我们是命运的主宰者
那是什么？交通警察
你确定你不是通缉犯？
没事，继续开
如果我开太快了，很对不起
没事，跟我来
我能请问…
午安，先生
本周是乔治华盛顿大桥周
纽约市将奖励第五千对
越过此桥的幸福情侣
这边，小姐
笑一个，小姐
不要动
对不起
我不能再给你高一点价
佩姬太太
你知道最近景气很差
祝福你
谢谢您，佩姬太太
喂！
佩姬太太吗？
又是你
你有带钱吗？
当然有
好吧，我们来点餐
我们要两个全熟大汉堡
一个要加辣椒
你知道你有什么问题吗
什么？
你的问题是事实上
你喜欢吃汉堡
但你不会承认的
我不知
你多久才想出那理论来
我猜我比你更了解你
是的
要来点沙律吗？
如果可以的话
我不相信你真的像装出来那样
我可告诉你
你真的太会说坏话
要腌黄瓜吗？
谢谢
你是在演戏
你跟我都知道金钱不是万能
谁跟你说的？
没有人
你有钱吗？
我有一点钱
那你怎么知道它不是万能呢
你真的相信
钱会为你带来快乐？
不，但它也不会让我难过
我不相信你，夏兹
听着，汤，我现在有麻烦了
你不明白吗？
我的财务出现大危机
如果那两个女孩不回来
我得拿出一年的房租
你觉得我现在该怎么做？
跟一个连领都没有的人
谈恋爱？
她们没写信给你吗？
怎么可能？她们是文盲
听着，甜心
没有的，汤
一旦我吃完这个马肉汉堡
我永远都不想再见到你
喂？
今天要不要去看自由女神像？
如果你有钱
那情况就不一样了
但我曾遇过像你这样的人
我真的是受够了
好吧，偏激小姐，看看那边吧
你暂时饶了我吧
事实上我不在乎你说什么
如果你没有钱
你已经没有钱了
我说过了没问题
你要我说什么？
一旦我们下了船
我永远都不想再见到你
喂
今晚如何？
不
我告诉你我是说真的
我们一到家
我永远不想再见…
对不起
我不能给你高点的价钱
佩姬太太
有这些钱我该偷笑了
总之再次地谢谢你
我可以进去吗？
我可以改变心意吗？
你是认真的吗？
我非常认真
你先等一下
佛瑞德
佛瑞德，我是佩姬太太
栏住家具行的人
告诉他立刻把东西搬上来
听清楚了吗？
别动
所以呢
好
怎么了，佩姬太太
我不知道，我觉得有点寂寞
是因为你的朋友吗
茔寸
我要那两个笨蛋站在我身边
还有半个小时，她们会来的
她们只要敢来
我扭断她们脖子
但我以为你…
我要她们昨天就来
我现在哪有时间笑她们
我的老天爷，好棒的派对
等一下
萝可来了
嗨
萝可，这是怎么一回事
今天夏兹要结婚，你不知吗
她要嫁给谁
一个来自德州达拉斯的人
对不起，我叫做叮当
您好
你有麻烦吗？
你是什么意思？
他完全被我迷住了
不会吧，他为我疯狂
你知道他身家有多少吗？
多少？
三千万
不会吧？
误差大概是一百万
那真是太棒了
他还是个完美的男人
我的天啊
我不是在说笑
这是场梦幻婚姻
你呢？你到底跑到哪里去了？
我又回缅因州去了
你回缅因州干嘛？
说真的，我在那里结婚了
不是跟那个混蛋吧
不，他结婚了
我也是那么想
你嫁给谁了？
他事实上不是个大人物
只是我在那里认识的一个男人
但我真的很爱他
一点都没错
我们都结婚了
他是干哪一行的？
他是个巡警
你是说他是开牧场的？
不，他是森林巡警
那不算太糟糕
若他有树也不错
木材很值钱的
你是怎么认识他的？
我不是说那些树是他的
他只是负责看守而已
你是说他只是看着它们？
他在山上有一匹马
他们得注意是否有火灾发生
那样子森林才不会被烧掉
他做那行怎么赚大钱啊？
他没甚么钱
你是说他是个消防队员？
没错
谢谢
汉利先生
法官大人
我想你有结婚许可
对，就在这里
你要见见他吗？
当然，他来了吗？
我去找他来
嗨，夏兹
我的老天爷
恭喜你，甜心
我们在飞机上知道你要结婚了
我觉得这真的是太棒了
你知道他有多少身家吗？
多少？
五千万
天啊
误差大概是一百万
你去买东西了吗？
商店一开门，我就立刻去买
我的天啊
你到哪里去了？
肯萨斯市
你做了甚么？
我跟佛莱迪在那里结婚了
你嫁给那个独眼龙？
不，对，但是…
我的天，宝娜，你需请个保姆
我在八岁时
就能看出那人是骗子
不是史都华，我嫁给佛莱迪了
佛莱迪？他是谁啊？
事情有点复杂
我搭飞机到肯萨斯去
我还以为你要去亚特兰大市
没错，但那班飞机的
第一个站是肯萨斯
没关系，我不想再听下去了
但告诉我一件事
他是不是有钱人？
是，但也不是
不，连你都一样
我是说只要解决了问题
他就是一个有钱人
你再说一次
他是个通缉犯
他是小偷
他不是小偷
事实上这间公寓是他的
但他把所得税交给了那个家伙
那么他为什么会被通缉？
然后他把那家伙的脖子打断了
但他的眼镜掉了
谁的眼镜？
佛莱迪的眼镜
那家伙差点打断了他的脖子
你是说他也是瞎子？
他视力比我还差
他来了
这位是夏兹，亲爱的
恭喜你，佩姬太太
谢谢，我也要恭喜你
她是个好女人
我想是的
这位是宝娜
很高兴能认识你
我的天啊
他很可爱吧
等一下
他再胖多两磅
她就得犯重婚罪了
对不起，佩姬太太
是的
汉利先生问是否有伴娘
如果他找得人的话就有
我可以当伴娘吗？
你现在算是已婚妇女了
我可以去跟他说吗？
去吧
来吧，甜心
别让宝娜抢在我前面
再见
只有夏兹在，来吧
他来了
嗨，佩姬太太
那是永久性的吗？
不，那只是护颈
他晚上会拿掉
别担心，我会报仇的
我只是得暂时避风头
我们在婚礼过后就要开始逃亡
你不介意吧
我很乐意
恭喜你
我们最好快点开始，夏兹
有些人等得很不耐烦了
好吧，请他奏乐吧
你确定吗？
当然
各位亲朋好友
我们今天齐聚到此
拜托
怎么了？亲爱的
我的膝盖
你能牵我走回去吗？
亲爱的，当然
你是个好男人
不该娶一个根本不爱你的人
就那样吗？
不然呢？
我能想出许多的理由
跟你证明你一开始就不爱我
我伤你伤得很重吗？
没错
但我会好起来的
听起来你像是已经好了
当你的年纪越来越大
失望成了日常生活
常见的一部份
你觉得我该怎么跟客人们说？
告诉他们佩姬太太疯了
我会好好安排的
你要跟萝可和宝娜谈谈吗？
那些笨蛋
你看到她们两个嫁给谁了吗？
对，我知道
萝可嫁给森林巡警
一个森林的消防队员
他看起来像是个好人
你看到宝娜的丈夫了吗？
没有
他是个通缉犯
不会吧
而且也是个大近视
他是个年轻人
就我所知，拆掉绷带后是的
他们彼此相爱，对吧？
没错，他们彼此相爱
那你的年轻人是谁？
什么年轻人？
你爱的那个年轻人
谁说我爱上一个年轻人了？
我说的
对，这很可耻
但我得承认，我是的
他是谁？
那重要吗？
我会好奇是很自然的
他是个无名小卒
一个很有性格的男人
他叫甚么名字？
布鲁文
布鲁文甚么？
汤布鲁文
你说他是个穷光蛋？
一个汉堡就打发他了
他是干哪一行的？
他没说，那对我也不重要
我已经知道了
什么？
他是加油站的工人
你怎么知道的？
我怎么知道
我只要一眼就可看穿那些家伙
我曾嫁给那种人，还记得吗？
他真的爱你吗？
他是那么说的
你为什么没嫁他？
那不重要的
那只是一种过程
他也在
在哪里？
外面
你怎么知道？
我觉得有个客人
长得很像加油站工人
他有打领带吗？
没有
这可是正式场合啊
你明白我的意思了吗？
这无关品味
你说得无错
在我跟他说
永远不想再见他后
谁想得到他会来
破坏我的婚礼？
我该去问问他
等一下，JD
您好吗？汤
我很好，我猜是吧
恭喜
恭喜你
别开玩笑了
你还是那么性格
有何不可呢？
她只要钱，她眼中只有钱
好吧，如果那是她要的
你尽管娶她吧
因为我不要她
她嘴吧上是那么说
但她心里不是那么想的
没错，发生了什么事？
她最后决定她要的是你
你在开玩笑吧？
不是
你跟她提过我的事吗？
当然没有
就她所知，你是加油站的工人
我不敢相信
好吧，我们去问她
等一下
等一下，JD
你觉得我现在该告诉她吗？
你疯了吗？
她喜欢加油站工人
胜过百万富翁
你要怎么做？
打破她的幻想吗？
布鲁克曼先生来了，亲爱的
你真的是太丢脸了
等一下
这是一场盛大的婚礼
你连领带都没有打
听我说，好吗？
其他人都穿正式服装
你却打扮成大学生的样子
听着，夏兹
我是说真的
我永远都不想再见到你
这次来个忌廉狗肉汉堡吧
那是个好主意
你觉得如何？
我要加辣椒
两个辣的
给她一杯饮料
还喜欢吗？
在婚礼结束后
大家来到一间很棒的汉堡店
吃着美味的狗肉汉堡
那些百万富翁每天都在谈什么？
这是百万富翁会遇到的事
我没什么好担心的
你身家大概有多少啊？亲爱的
我想应该是十四元左右
误差在五毫钱左右
没错，而且全都是现金
你呢？杀手，你有多少钱？
说真的，如果我能解决问题
当然
我知道他的钱都被冻结了
他是个有钱人
但他是个通缉犯
等一下，我想听骄傲先生说
你的身家有多少？
我想大约是两亿吧
那没什么
或许全都是现金吧？
如果有需要的话
我应该可以拿出几百万来
真的是太简单了
那其他钱在哪里？
有一些在石油上
有一些航空公司的股票
一些钢铁工厂
在德州还有牧场
在阿拉巴马有两个煤矿
到处都有点物业
一些汽车股票
布鲁克曼大楼
当然了，还有布鲁克曼宾州
整个城市都是他的
我们都有，我们有牛，钢铁厂
我遇到什么样的男人了
我喜欢一个城市
以我的名字命名
我要结帐了，马克
苏海多爱达荷州
对，宝娜伊利诺州
还有萝可…
零钱你就留着吧，马克
男士们
敬我们的太太
剧终
谢谢观赏
[Music Playing ]
[Up Tempo]
[ Slower Tempo]
[Ends]
[Up Tempo]
New York, New York
You high and mighty, bright and shiny
fabulous place, New York
New York, New York
You busy, dizzy, razzle-dazzle
scandalous place, New York
Guys with easy money
tryin' to blow it
Dolls with hidden talent
dyin' to show it
Take off for Broadway
by taxi, by subway
And land on the town
A merry-go-round
New York, New York
Where millionaires and Cinderellas
rendezvous at the Stork
In Central Park romantic babies
and their fellas rendezvous in the dark
Crazy city with its hat
on the steeple
Noisy city with
its millions of people
Doorway to glory
and fortune and fame
You'll never get your fill of it
never forget the thrill of it
Glorious, glamorous
wonderland
New York
Oh, is Mr. Benton here yet,
the agent for the apartments?
Oh, yes. He's in there
waiting for you now.
Thank you.
Oh, good morning, Mrs. Page.
I do hope I haven't
kept you waiting too long.
Not in the least. I'm afraid I have
a little disappointment for you, though.
You won't be able to meet Mr. Denmark.
He flew to Europe this morning.
Oh, dear, I am disappointed.
Wasn't that awfully sudden?
Oh, very. You know how those income tax
people are when you skip a whole year.
And the result, of course, is that
a longer lease is now possible.
Open, if you don't mind.
Hmm? Oh, oh, certainly.
Certainly.
How long a lease? Not that it matters
if he's to insist on a thousand a month.
That's what I wanted to
see him about, personally.
Oh, he won't be needing
the place for years now.
I hear Mr. Whiskers really
blew his top this time.
You mean he can't come back
to this country?
It would be I understand
the very height of folly.
Oh, I see. Well, it throws
an entirely different light.
Where's that lease?
Well, I'm afraid
I haven't got it with me.
Oh, never mind.
You can mail it to me.
This is for two months,
the first and the last.
- That's the deal, isn't it?
- That's correct.
How soon would you like
to take possession?
Oh, anything wrong
with right now?
Nothing at all. It's a little unusual,
of course, but, uh...
Thank you so much, Mr. Benton.
You've been awfully kind.
Oh, thank you, Mrs. Page.
It's a genuine pleasure to do business
with a woman of such decision.
- We in the real estate game...
- Bye now.
Oh, yes, of course. Well.
Oh, I almost forgot.
How long shall I make the lease for?
Oh, a year will be quite enough.
Thank you.
But don't you think
you oughta have it...
-[ Woman ] Yes?
- Bingo.
I'll be right over.
- To the left.
- Thanks.
All right, put 'em on.
No men here yet.
You certainly got here in a hurry.
Did you take a taxi?
No, I didn't have
enough money for a taxi
I had the Chrysler people demonstrate
that new showboat for me again.
- The one with the gold trim?
- Was it gold?
I didn't want to put on my specs
with the driver there, you know.
The one they sent for me
had gold trim.
Brother!
Smooth, huh?
Creamy. Are we really in?
- Built in.
- I'll call Loco.
Loco who?
You know, that girl
I was telling you about from Jersey.
You didn't tell me
her name was "Loco."
It isn't. That's what the other models
call her. It means crazy, you know?
That's what I know.
- Hello?
- Bingo!
- Hold that for a minute.
- Just a minute, Loke.
I can't shack up with a dame I haven't
even met, and she's crazy too.
You don't have to. All I'm going to
ask her is to come up here.
If you don't like her,
that's the end of it.
- Is she class?
- Is she. Didn't I tell you?
She's been on the cover of
Harper's Bazaar three times already.
And she knows
how to handle it?
- Well, let's see if she does. Loke?
- Yes?
- How much money you got?
- I've got a quarter.
That's wonderful. Stop in on your way
up here and pick up lunch for us.
- How many?
- Three.
Okay. Just as soon
as I get something on.
There's a fine contribution to a million
dollar proposition, one whole quarter.
Maybe, but she's awful
clever with a quarter.
I just don't know how I'll ever
be able to thank you enough.
-[ Doorbell Buzzes]
- I'm still so embarrassed.
You have no reason to be. Anybody can
forget their money. I've done it myself.
I know, but...
Oh, hi, honey.
- Come on in.
- Come in.
This is a gentleman I met
at the cold cuts counter.
- What did you say your name was?
- Tom Brookman.
B-R-O-O-K-M-A-N.
Brookman.
Well, this is my friend,
Miss Pola Debevoise.
- How do you do?
- Oh, and this is Miss Page, isn't it?
- Mrs. Page.
- How do you do? It was very funny.
I was ordering some pastrami
and potato salad,
and I heard Miss Dempsey explaining
she only had a quarter...
You can just set that down.
We'll take it from here.
Oh, wouldn't you like me
to put them in the kitchen?
No, I don't think you'd better.
The cook's not dressed.
- Oh, really?
- Thank you very much.
Some other day.
Give us a ring next week.
- I don't know your number.
- That's all right. It's in the book.
Thank you very much,
Mr. Brookman.
- But I don't know your first name.
- He was really very nice.
I thought he might
have lunch with us.
Look, the first rule of this proposition
is that gentleman callers
have got to wear a necktie.
I don't want to be snobbish,
but if we begin with characters like that,
we might just as well
throw in the towel right now
Thanks, Mick.
Keep the change.
- How do, Mr. Brookman?
- Hiya, Pete.
The next thing to remember is
a gentleman you meet among cold cuts
is simply not as attractive
as one that you meet,
say in the mink department
at Bergdorf's.
But he was cute,
don't you think?
Sure he was, but then I never met one
of those gas pump jockeys that wasn't.
- Is that what he is?
- You bet your life.
I know those guys. I married one once.
Very, very cute fellow.
- I didn't know you were really married.
- Just got back from Reno.
Oh, then you must be loaded.
Mine was one of those divorces you don't
read about. The wife finished second.
But that's against the law, isn't it?
I was absolutely nuts about that guy,
and you know what he did to me?
First off, he gives me
a phony name.
Second, it turns out
he was already married yet.
Third, from the minute
the preacher said, "Amen,"
he never did
another tap of work.
The next thing I knew he'd stolen my
television set and given it to a carhop.
When I ask him how about that,
he hits me with a chicken.
- A live chicken?
- No, a baked chicken, stuffed.
He sounds incompatible to me.
Last I saw of him, I stepped out of
the car for a minute at a gas station.
I had to walk home.
[ Loco ] Well, I'm surprised
you'd ever want to get married again.
Oh, but that's the point
about this whole setup.
Of course I want to
get married again.
Who doesn't?
It's the biggest thing
you can do in life.
The way most people go about it,
they use more brains
picking a horse in the third at Belmont
than they do picking a husband.
- Do they really?
- It's your head you've got to use,
-not your heart.
- Oh, I see.
Tell her your idea
about this apartment.
Well, to put it simply,
the idea is this.
If you had your choice
of everybody in the world,
which would you rather marry,
a rich guy or a poor one?
I think I'd rather marry a rich one.
All right. Where would you
be most likely to meet a rich one,
in a walk-up on Amsterdam Avenue
or in a joint like this?
Well...
I should say in a joint like this.
Okay, then, that's it.
We're all working steady,
so we throw everything
we make into the kitty,
and get a little organization
into this marriage caper.
Class address, class background,
class characters.
To be specific about it,
nothing under six figures a year.
I've never heard anything
so intelligent in my life.
If you want to catch a mouse,
you set a mousetrap.
So, all right,
we set a bear trap.
All we've got to do is one of us
has got to knock off a bear.
- You mean marry him?
- If you don't marry him,
you haven't caught him,
he's caught you.
All my life, ever since I was a little
girl, I've had the same dream,
to marry a zillionaire.
Do you know who I'd like to marry?
- Who?
- Rockefeller.
- Which one?
- I don't care.
I wouldn't mind marrying
a Vanderbilt.
Or a Mr. Cadillac.
No such person. I checked.
Is there a Mr. Texaco?
No. But how about one
of those rich maharajas?
How about three of them?
Wouldn't it be wonderful if we had three
of them for dinner and they married us?
Think of all those
diamonds and rubies.
And all those crazy elephants.
This is really living it up, isn't it?
People that live any other way
are just crazy.
I wonder who's going to pay for it.
- Yeah, how about that?
- Well, I'll tell you.
-[ Doorbell Buzzes ]
- I knew it couldn't last.
Relax, will you? And somebody
break open that other bottle.
Good afternoon. I'm Mr. Bennett
of the Bennett Music Company.
- Are you the lady...
- That's right. Come right in.
Thank you.
The reason I called you is,
what will you give me
for this piano, cash?
Well,
it's a very handsome instrument.
[ Piano]
Really, Pola, I think she's the most
intelligent person I guess I ever met.
Well, it's not in first-class condition,
you understand,
but, uh, we might be interested
in paying you, say 2,500?
We'll take it.
Well, kids,
where will we eat tonight,
the Stork or 21?
-[ Phone Ringing ]
- Hello?
[ Man ] Is this Trafalgar 7-5098?
- Yes?
- Who's this, Miss Page?
- Yes, who is this?
- This is Tom Brookman.
- Oh.
- You remember me.
- Oh, sure, but...
- Well, I kept thinking about you,
but I didn't realize who you were till I
picked up an old magazine this morning.
- What do you mean?
- You were Miss Steinbach Beer last year.
Why, yes, I believe I was.
And isn't that you jumping around in
a girdle in all those ads in magazines?
I wouldn't exactly call it "jumping around."
I'm supposed to be dancing.
Reason I called, I was wondering if you
wouldn't have dinner with me some night.
Whatever night you say.
What about tonight?
- I'm afraid I can't tonight.
- Tomorrow night?
- I'm sorry.
- What about Thursday night?
Mr. Brookman, you're wasting your time
on this number. Don't call it again.
[Sighs]
Hey, kid!
- Pola?
- Yes?
Do you think we'll ever be able
to get this job off the ground?
- What do you mean?
- Here we are nearly three months,
and we can't even get ourselves
engaged, much less married.
- I could have got engaged last week.
- To?
- That English fellow.
- What English fellow?
You know, that tall one that
borrowed five dollars from me.
That's what I mean. Here we are
set up strictly for the carriage train,
and what do we get, you hook a schnook
who takes you for a fin,
I get an invitation
to Hamburger Heaven for dinner,
and Loco shows up every evening with
a gentleman she's met in the drugstore,
with five more shower caps
and three quarts of aspirin tablets.
And where do you think
that's gonna get us?
I don't think it's us.
I think it's the men these days.
They're getting more and more nervous,
especially the loaded ones.
Meanwhile, where are
we gonna sit next week?
Well, we're both trying, you know.
It isn't always easy
to find out right away
how much they're worth
or if they're married or not.
They look at you like you're
prying into their private affairs.
Something's got to break soon,
or we're gonna be out on the sidewalk.
And all we need, you know,
is just one.
That's the beautiful thing
about a bear trap.
You don't have to catch
a whole herd of them,
all you need is
one nice, big, fat one.
[ Doorbell Buzzes ]
Probably Miss Perth Amboy again
with another load of dollar-day Kleenex.
Thanks.
- Oh, hello, Schatze.
- Hello.
This is... I'm sorry.
What did you say your name was?
- Hanley. J.D. Hanley.
- Of course.
This is Schatze Page,
and this is Pola Debevoise.
- How do you do?
- How do you do, ladies?
I met Mr. Hanley
in the mink department at Bergdorf's.
- Really?
- Yes, the clerk was nice enough to...
You'll have to excuse
the state of this apartment.
We've just sent everything out
to be cleaned.
But if you don't mind
coming into the dining room.
Oh, of course not.
And with the maid off today,
we're roughing it, you might say.
- Won't you sit down?
- Oh, thank you very much, but I can't stay.
I just came along to help
Miss Dempsey with her bundle.
Mr. Hanley's from Dallas, Texas.
Oh, really?
In the oil business?
Oh, a little oil, but mostly stock.
- Stocks and bonds?
- No, none of that sort of thing for me.
My stock is
white-faced Hereford, polled.
- Come again?
- Cattle.
- You know, like cows.
- Oh, I see.
Are you sure you won't sit down
for just a little while?
Oh, I haven't time right now. But what
I was talking to Miss Dempsey about,
there's a little organization that
I'm a member of, the Oil Institute.
Kind of elder statesmen
of the business.
We're having a little informal
reception tonight.
If you young ladies would
honor us with your presence,
I'm sure you'd make us
all very happy, indeed.
Do you mean
nothing but oil men?
Well, not exactly.
Probably a few bankers too.
Well, bankers will be all right.
- Don't you think?
- Naturally.
I realize this is a little sudden
and unconventional,
but there will be dancing and
a few drinks and a few laughs perhaps.
- Sounds just creamy to me.
- I like laughs.
- Well, then it's a deal?
- I'd love it.
That's wonderful. I'll pick you up
around 8:30, if that's all right.
Will we meet some of
the other gentlemen too?
Oh, all of them. And don't worry,
they're not all old crooks like me.
- What on earth!
- Stop it!
You look just in the prime to me.
Thank you, ladies. You've already
made my trip to New York worthwhile.
Bye now.
I think this is it, kids.
A great big room full of nothing
but rich millionaires
and us.
[Man ] This brings us down to 1947.
I think it's a very good idea.
Where should we go?
Well, there's a new place...
Good evening, madame.
Good evening, sir.
- Table for two.
- Certainly, sir.
This way, madame.
- Champagne?
- We might as well.
Oh, a table for two, Philip.
Certainly, madame.
Will you come this way?
- The best, you know.
- Certainly, sir.
The best we have, sir.
- A quart of champagne.
- What kind, sir?
- The best you've got.
- Very good, sir.
- Good evening.
- Good evening. Two, please.
This way, please.
- This way, my dear.
- I'm so sorry.
Oh, I am sorry.
Did you say
you were alone here?
Oh, there's quite a party
of us up from Texas.
- All men?
- Oh, some wives too.
You met some of them this evening.
The others went to a show.
You know how the women are
when they get to New York.
I know.
I think Ella has seen five shows
in the last three days.
- I see.
- Ella's my daughter.
- Oh, really?
- Mm.
Is Mrs. Merrill here with you?
There is no Mrs. Merrill,
and I live in New York.
Does that clear the situation
a bit for you?
Oh, yes, indeedy,
it does.
Are you married?
Married? I sometimes think
I'm the most married man in the U.S.A.
Do you know how many females were
at my house when I left there tonight?
No. I can't say that I do.
Seven, my wife, her sister,
who's divorced.
And I don't blame the guy
for a second.
Their mother, who must be 110
if she's a day.
An aunt from
North Attleboro, Massachusetts.
And three more whose names
I didn't even catch.
To tell the truth, I...
I never really felt the loneliness
of being a widower
until the past few years.
At first, there were children,
you know, to keep me company.
But they're grown up now.
My son's married. Ella's engaged.
I must confess the house is beginning
to seem pretty big and empty.
I can imagine.
I suppose that's why I've done
so much travelling lately.
London, south of France,
Scotland and so on.
That's really no good, you know.
Oh, no, I know.
No good at all.
Couple of years ago,
I chartered a boat.
Not large, but quite comfortable.
Took about six months,
just loafing around the world.
But it was no use.
I suppose there's really only
one cure for loneliness.
- Yes?
- Human companionship.
Oh, but you're so right.
You just don't know how right you are.
I'm not accustomed really to going out
publicly with a married man.
And if I'd had a chance
to ask you at the party,
I don't know that I would have
accompanied you here.
Well, this is all quite innocent, isn't it?
If it is, it's the first time I ever
ran into it under similar circumstances.
Of course, my first impulse was
to go directly to Arabia myself
and take a good look-see
at the situation.
I was certain those chaps from Socony
Standard of New Jersey...
would have somebody on the spot.
After all, there's quite
a tidy little sum involved,
two or three hundred million.
- I wasn't going to take any chances.
- Well, naturally.
Trouble is it looks like I've got a thing
for guys who work in gas stations.
I never met one yet
that didn't send me.
This one handled a pump
for Standard Oil.
You don't own that, do you?
Oh, no, no. Standard Oil
is one of the interests
of a man named,
I believe, Rockefeller.
Is he a friend of yours?
No, no, I'm afraid not.
Oh, well. But as I was saying...
When you live in
a lunatic asylum like that,
you've got to get out of town
every now and then.
- You know what I mean?
- Perfectly.
I've got that all fixed now.
I've got me a lodge up in Maine.
I love lodges.
- You do?
- Simply adore them.
You mean, uh,
you'd like to see mine?
Oh, well, I was speaking
more figuratively than relatively.
Because if you would,
I'm going up there Friday afternoon.
Simply adore 'em!
If you wanna know
what kind of a guy I've got...
All I can say is
I'm a very happy woman.
Not only is Mr. Hanley a perfect doll,
but he's absolutely unaffiliated.
- You don't think he's a little old?
- Grow up, will you?
Men with that much dough
are never a little old.
Mine's loaded too,
but he's a real yawn.
- He doesn't look single to me either.
- He's not.
- What are you wasting time on him for?
- What else have I got?
Unless you'd like me to lose him
and join you and your friend.
You do, and I'll break your neck
in front of this restaurant.
- Besides, he's invited me to a party.
- Oh, yeah? When?
We're leaving
Friday afternoon.
- Leaving for where?
- His lodge in Maine.
- You out of your mind?
- I don't think so. I like lodges.
You can't go.
It's a violation of the whole idea.
Why is it? I could meet somebody
else up there, couldn't I?
Who are you going to
meet in Maine, Eskimos?
Did you see this fellow I'm with?
- I saw him.
- What's he look like?
- Very nice for a one-eyed man.
- Is that all he's got?
What do you think
he's got that patch on for?
I didn't know it was a patch. I thought
somebody might have belted him.
Why can't you keep those cheaters on
long enough to see who you're with?
I'm not going to
take a chance like that.
You know what they say
about girls who wear glasses.
Maybe somebody shot him
in the eye.
He sounds just wonderful. I was
curious to know what he looked like.
- Who is he?
- I don't know that either.
But he hasn't mentioned anything
under a million dollars yet.
My guy's real class. Never mentions
his wealth, just refers to it.
All Mr. Brewster talks about
is what a horrible family he's got.
But I'll say this for him,
we haven't ordered anything yet
under five dollars a portion.
If there's anything leftover,
tell the waiter you want it for the dog.
We'd better be getting back
before they cool off.
Where's Maine, anyway?
[ Mooing ]
I'll take that and that
and that and that.
And that and that.
And that and that
and that and that.
- And charge it.
- Certainly, Mrs. Hanley.
[ Propellers Whirring ]
Next stop Arabia, sir.
[ Speaking Arabic]
-[ In Arabic]
- Is he kidding?
- Not at all.
It's an old custom of the East
to make the stranger feel welcome.
You can tell him from me
I think he's simply a doll,
and I couldn't be crazier
about these old Eastern customs.
Hello, Fashion House?
ls Mr. Antoine in for Mr. Brookman?
Thank you.
Mr. Antoine?
On the phone.
-Tony? Hiya, boy.
-Yes?
- How are you?
- Fine, fine.
How are you fixed for stuff for Florida,
beach stuff and all that?
- You mean ultra?
- I got an aunt I want to get stuff for.
- How old is she?
- About 25. A very young type aunt.
- I'm sure I could accommodate you.
- Could I see it on them?
- Today?
- That's right. That's the idea.
Tony, you know a model
named Schatze?
- Who?
- Schatze.
- Oh, Mrs. Page.
- That's the one.
- Oh, nice joint you got here, Tony.
- Thank you, sir.
- Please sit here.
- If you'll excuse me.
Your aunt,
is she blond or brunette?
It depends entirely
on the weather.
The way I'm going to handle it,
I'm not going to stall with Mr. Hanley.
What are you going to do,
mother him?
No, that's all right for kids,
but I don't think a mother
is exactly what Mr. Hanley
has in mind.
Our first we call
"Rainbow Over the Everglades."
It's a pastel plaid, silk organza
day dress with a voluminous skirt
for cocktail parties
and afternoon gatherings.
You know, of course,
that diamonds are a girl's best friend.
And this is our proof of it.
You're not really thinking of going
away with that chowderhead, are you?
Oh, for heaven's sake, no!
- You're on, Loke.
- Oh, goodness!
This one we call
"Looky,Looky,LookyP
It begins as
a spectator's sports dress.
- Well, get you.
- Hi.
Which converts into
a one-piece play costume
of Jersey
and checked-matching wool.
Our next we call
"Good Afternoon, Sweetheart."
This is an afternoon tea dress, which
plunges in the back rather than the front.
Made of imported printed sheer,
with parasol to match.
You like that, monsieur?
Comme ci, comme ?a.
That guy's really
the end of the line.
I still think he's kinda cute.
- Who is he?
- That garage man.
- What garage?
- That fella I got with the cold cuts.
"Trouble in the Afternoon." A beach
boy's shirt of pink and white gingham,
with a deep rose crushed cummerbund.
And a coolie hat of natural straw.
"Hard-Hearted Hannah"
is a Palm Beach stroller
consisting of
mustard crash pants
and a shirttail blouse
of grey and white silk.
Next we have
"Double Frozen Daiquiris."
A beach costume of sleek
blue pants of fine wool,
with a wrap around of Thai silk.
You will notice the Egyptian influence
in the bizarre raffia hat.
"South of the Border" is Mexican crepe
of black cotton twill,
a tamale-colored serape
and a peon straw hat.
Could I take another look
at that pink-and-blue job?
But of course, sir. Miss Schatze.
- Much obliged, Tony.
- Not at all, sir.
Did you see anything
I could put aside for you?
Nope. I don't see anything here
that I want. Thanks again, Tony.
[Woman ] All right, girls. Thank you.
- Mr. Antoine?
- Yes?
- I know that guy. He's a screw pot.
- A screw pot?
- He's making a chump out of you.
- Miss Schatze.
- Yes?
- Do I tell you how to put on a girdle?
You bet your sweet life you don't.
Then, would you be good enough
not to tell me how to run my business?
[Whistle Blows]
Shh!
[Bell Dinging]
[Train Hisses]
- Mr. Brewster?
- Yes.
I'll take these.
[Train Whistle Blows]
Aboard!
You're not the regular
driver, are you?
No, sir.
Pa's the regular driver.
But he went to a Republican rally last
night and didn't get up this morning.
It certainly is
a funny place for it.
Funny place for what?
A convention.
- What's this?
- The lodge, naturally.
This house?
It'll look better
when I get a fire going.
- But where are the others?
- Other what?
- Members.
- I'm sorry, Miss Dempsey.
I don't know what you're talking
about half the time. What members?
- You said it was a lodge, didn't you?
- I did and it is.
Then, where are the members.
Like the Elks Lodge.
Mother and I went to an Elks Lodge
convention in Philadelphia,
and there were thousands
of members there.
It was one of the happiest
times of our life.
Is that what you really
thought this was?
Well, naturally.
What else?
- Where do you want these?
- Back in the car.
What's the matter?
Something wrong?
No, just going back
to New York, that's all.
Well, not today, you're not.
No more trains till tomorrow.
Oh, I may slit my throat.
- Would you like a fire?
- I was about to...
That's all right.
I'll do it.
Never saw so much snow
in my life.
I'm sorry about all this.
If you'll just be patient,
I'll try to get you out of here
as soon as I possibly can.
I figured I might have to put on some
of those skis, but not in all this snow.
I'll tell you what. I have
some old Medford rum in the pantry.
I'll get a drink for you. And meanwhile,
maybe you'd like a little music.
Meanwhile, maybe I'd like
a little poison too.
[ Radio: "You'll Never Know
How Much I Love You" ]
You got radio
all the way up here?
Oh, sure.
Radio and houses, everything.
Here. Maybe you'd better
take the first one straight.
Just listen to that music, all the way
from New York. Good ol' Harry James.
Is it really?
How can you tell?
Oh, I can tell it's Harry James
because it is Harry James.
Ladies and gentlemen, you are listening
to the music of Ziggy Colombo,
-coming to you from the...
- Turn that liar off.
Why don't you stop acting like
a spoiled brat and behave yourself?
I've never been mixed up
in a situation like this before.
As long as I'm in my right mind,
I never will again.
But it's not doing either of us any good
to stand here and jaw at each other.
I feel awful.
All tingly.
Well, I wish I did.
Drink it. Drink it.
Is this rum?
Medford Rum.
It's over 100 years old.
Then I'm sick. I've got a fever.
Call a doctor immediately.
- What are you talking about?
- I've got a fever, I tell you.
Whenever rum smells like a carnation,
I've got a fever.
We've got to get
a doctor right away.
- There's no reason to get hysterical.
- Don't you hit me!
I'm not going to hit you.
I want to feel your forehead.
- There's a thermometer outside the door.
- Get it! Get it!
Will you please call a doctor?
I know when I've got a fever.
You do feel
a little warm.
Are you going to call
a doctor or not?
I can't call a doctor. Everybody knows
me here. Don't you understand?
What am I supposed to do, die because
you got a big name around here?
- It's a little large, but...
-ls there a hospital around here?
- Open your mouth.
- What's that?
- I want to take your temperature.
- Not with that flute.
It's not a flute,
it's a thermometer. Look.
That's not for people,
it's for blizzards.
Open your mouth, I tell you.
And don't you try to talk
until I take that out.
If it was my daughter,
you know what I'd do?
Well, she's not your daughter.
She's not my daughter either,
if that's what you're driving at.
- How much is it?
- One hundred and two.
- Is that bad?
- It's definitely a slight temperature.
Maybe you call it slight
in the city of New York,
but in Maine,
she oughta be in bed.
I'm gonna die. I know it.
I'm gonna die out here
in this jungle!
If you want, I'll call Ma.
She's a practical nurse.
- Oh, what good will that do?
- We can tell her the symptoms.
She'll give us the answers.
All right. But be very careful
what you tell her.
I'll tell her what you
tell me to tell her.
[Phone Ringing]
Hazel? Eben.
Ring Ma, will ya?
Brewster's Lodge.
Yeah, he's here with...
- Shh!
- His skis.
If it's mumps, I'll die.
Ma? Say, what's it a sign of
when a girl is shivering and shaking
and has a temperature of 102?
- Her eyes watering?
- Like two faucets.
They're watering.
Look at her tongue.
It looks kind of red.
Tongue's blotchy.
Look behind her ears.
Have you been
scratching yourself?
Of course not.
Models aren't allowed to scratch.
Breaking out behind the ears.
Uh-huh.
I see. Okay, thanks, Ma.
- You got nothing to worry about.
- What is it?
- Measles.
- Measles!
And I've got nothing
to worry about.
"Get her to bed," Ma says.
Keep her quiet and the room dark
so you can avoid complications.
She'll be as good as new
in a week or two.
[Sobbing ] Oh!
- Keep it.
- Much obliged.
Yes, sir.
- Hi, Mike.
- Well, for goodness sakes.
How are you, Mr. Denmark?
I thought you were in Europe.
I was. Come back here.
You're a friend of mine, aren't you?
- You bet your life, sir.
- Yeah, well,
I'm in a little jam with the income
tax department, and I need your help.
Anything you want, sir.
I've had a little trouble
with those people myself
from time to time.
- Who's got my apartment now?
- Three young ladies, sir.
- Business women, I believe.
- Yeah, well,
I gotta get in there for a few minutes.
Think you can arrange it?
You can get in there now, sir.
They're both out for the evening.
One of them's with a Texas fellow,
and the other's with the one-eyed man
- How about the other one?
- Oh, she's away at an Elks convention.
- You want me to wait here?
- Yeah, if you can.
- If I get a buzz, I'll come back.
-[ Buzzer Buzzes]
That's not them.
They never get in till 2:00 or 3:00.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay if I turn on the lights?
Sure.
[ Schatze] Pola must have left the lights on.
- What will you have to drink?
- Milk, if you don't mind.
Milk?
Well, if we've got any.
Go to the kitchen, will you?
I'll be there in a minute.
[ Soft Music]
Is that the best we've got?
Apparently, but it's all I want.
Schatze, you've made my visit
a very pleasant one.
I'd like to do something
to show my appreciation.
Oh, don't be silly, J.D.
Tell me something. Is this furniture
really out to be cleaned,
or is there
some other explanation?
You don't have to
worry about that.
Did you sell it or hock it?
Well, we sold it.
Will they sell it back?
And now, dear Schatze,
I'm afraid
we must say good-bye.
Good-bye? But I thought
you were staying until next week.
I was, but something has happened
that I would never have dreamed of.
And I think the wisest thing I can do
is to get out of here at once.
What do you mean?
Do you remember the first time I came
into this apartment with Loco?
Yes.
I came in here a subtle and aging widower,
with a pattern of my life all laid out
for the rest of my days.
- Really?
- That isn't the way I went out of here.
You didn't?
Tell me, do you believe
in love at first sight?
Oh, absolutely, J.D.
No question in the world about it.
Well, I don't.
Not at my age, anyway.
Stop talking about your age. You'd
think you were as old as Methuselah.
Don't you know you're right
in the very prime of life?
How old are you?
Forty.
[ Chuckles] Oh, Schatze, Schatze.
That's probably the sweetest lie
you've ever told.
Twenty-five would be
a little more like it, wouldn't it?
But look here, J.D. You don't want
to go jumping to conclusions, do you?
Look, it's no use, darling.
I'm 56 years old.
Thirty years older than you.
By your standards, anyway,
an old man.
- Oh, no.
- We might support this difference
for another
four to five years perhaps,
but what happens
when I'm truly old?
But listen, J.D.
I hate young men.
-[ Gasps ] Thank you very much.
- That's all right.
- Have you got to go already?
- I'm afraid so.
- Well, nighty-night.
- Good night.
I've always liked older men.
Look at Roosevelt.
Look at Churchill.
Look at that old fellow
what's-his-name in African Queen.
Absolutely crazy about him.
- So, you see, J.D...
- Pardon me.
- Hello. Come in.
- Hope I'm not intruding.
You're entitled to such
a hope, I believe.
[Chuckles] Don't let her kid you, Pola.
I've got to be going, anyway.
- So early?
- Yes, I'm flying home tomorrow morning.
- Oh, no.
- I've got to.
Good-bye, my dear. It's been
a great pleasure knowing all you girls.
Good-bye, J.D.
Come back, will you?
I will. Someday, perhaps.
Good-bye.
[ Schatze ] What time
does your plane leave?
9200.
Don't you believe
anything I say at all?
I believe that nothing could have been
more wonderful for me than marrying you.
And nothing worse for you.
- Will you call me before you go?
- That's too early for you.
Very well.
Good night, darling.
What's the matter?
I oughta punch you
right smack in the nose.
- What did I do?
- Nothing.
Nothing but break up a play
at the two-yard line, that's all.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry, Schatze.
Really I am.
Little Miss Bubblehead
is terribly, terribly sorry, indeed.
I was just so anxious
to tell you the news.
- What news?
- We're going to be married.
- You and who?
- Me and Stewart.
You mean Blinky?
Yes. And if he doesn't have to
fly to London this weekend,
he's going to take me down
to meet his mother this Saturday.
- Down where?
- Atlantic City.
Oh. What did you say
this guy did?
Oil, darling.
Simply barrels of it.
- Says he, huh?
- But of course.
You ought to hear him
talk about it, really.
I think we oughta put
a check on that one.
Why? I don't know
what you mean.
Nobody's mother lives
in Atlantic City on Saturday.
[Ring]
- Hello?
- Miss Page?
That's right, it's still no.
Oh! Oh!
[ Screams ]
[Laughs]
Oh!
Now who on earth
ever thought of this?
- Thought of what?
- Skiing on snow.
What else would you ski on?
Why, the natural way,
like in Florida, on water.
Ski on water? Why you.
Oh, no!
Mrs. Salem!
Here she is now.
[Humming] How are you feeling?
Never mind how I feel.
Where have you been?
- Sitting on the mountain.
- Who with?
Nobody.
- What's that?
- I'm going to give you a manicure.
- What was his name?
- Eben.
You gotta be careful. You don't want to
get mixed up with a fellow like that.
- Don't I?
- Never.
Who do you think I oughta
get mixed up with?
Well, I won't always
have measles, you know.
Say, you are getting better.
You just wait till
we get back to New York.
- I don't dig you sometimes.
- What do you mean?
- Is your wife a spook?
- Of course not.
She's a very wonderful woman
and a true credit to her sex.
- Oh, brother!
- I mean it.
- Then, Why'd you flip like this?
- Pardon?
What set you off that night?
Oh! Well, for one thing,
-you're a very beautiful young woman.
- I know.
And for another,
I was a little upset that evening.
My daughter had just
run away and got married.
Well, for goodness sakes,
what's wrong with that?
What was wrong with that
was the fella's no good. He's a gigolo.
Oh, really? Maybe I know him.
What's his name?
- His name's Martinez.
- I read about that.
He's a dancer.
"Hoofer Weds Heiress."
Well, she isn't one any more.
- What do you mean?
- I disinherited her.
Disinherited her?
Well, there's one thing
I'll say for poor people,
they don't go around
disinheriting their children.
Obviously. They've got nothing
to disinherit them with.
Say that again.
Poor families don't have any money to
pass on from one generation to another.
It doesn't make
any difference.
My mother, no matter how much money
she didn't have, she wouldn't disinherit me.
Do you mind if we just
don't talk for a while?
Not at all.
I like not to talk.
This is what
I wanted you to see.
It's nice.
It's all mine from the crest
of that second ridge to the north there,
all the way around
as far as the eye can see to the west
and back around that way
to just beyond old Baldy.
- All yours?
- Yep.
You mean all those trees
and mountains and everything?
That's it.
Well, for crying out loud.
Isn't it beautiful?
Isn't that what they call "timber"?
Best in the world.
Well, what do you know
about that?
I think it's the most beautiful sight
in the whole world.
Well, I certainly
don't blame you.
Pure and as clean
and plenty of room.
Do you, uh, think
you could ever come to like it?
Well, I never thought
about it before,
but I imagine I could.
You should see it at night, with the
moon and the stars over that mountain.
Look, show me again
how much is yours.
Well, from the crest of
that second ridge to the north there,
all the way around
to the west.
[ Horns Blare]
It's all right this time.
One went to work,
one went to look at a bank and
the other one is still with the Elks.
If I remember correctly,
that's what you said the other night.
I know, but this time I'm positive.
[Phone Rings 1
[Ring]
Hello?
Oh, hello.
- Hello.
- Just a moment.
- She's not back yet.
- She isn't?
- You wanna wait?
- Uh, no thanks. I'd better be going.
- I'll tell her you were here.
- Thank you.
- Bye now.
- Bye.
Sorry, darling. Just one of Schatze's
friends just popped in to say hello.
- I'll tell you what I want you to do.
- Yes?
It seems that I've got to nip down
to Washington this evening for dinner
with a certain party
whose name I'll tell you later.
But that means I'll probably
have to stay there overnight.
So, I'm going to ask you to take
the plane down to Atlantic City alone,
and I'll be over from Washington
in time to meet you at the airport.
- Is that all right?
- Of course it is, darling.
Then, here's a schedule
I suggest
There's a flight from Atlantic City
from La Guardia Airport at 5:00 P.M.
Fasten your seat belts, please.
May I take these, please?
Well, everything's okay.
Well, I'll be darned.
Pardon?
Haven't we met before?
For goodness sakes, you're that friend
of Schatze's. What happened to you?
- When?
- Yesterday.
I told Schatze you were coming back,
and she waited for you.
Uh, I got tied up.
- Your wife?
- Oh, I'm not married.
That's nice.
- Um, look.
- Yes?
Didn't you bring your glasses?
What glasses?
Don't you wear glasses?
Oh, no. Whatever gives you that idea?
You got the most peculiar
vision I ever saw.
- Why do you say that?
- You're reading that book upside down.
But I'm no such thing.
Not you, the book.
Oh.
Isn't it silly, though?
What is it, astigmatism?
- No, just blind as a bat.
- Me too.
Oh, really?
Then, why aren't you
wearing glasses?
I am wearing glasses.
Well, there you are.
I used to be like that. For years,
I went around banging into fireplugs
and shaking hands with lampposts because
I didn't want to be called four eyes.
And then, something happened which
cured me of that sort of thing forever.
What was that?
One evening, I said hello to three
different fellows I owed money to.
But it's different with girls,
don't you think?
How is it?
Well, you know what they say
about girls who wear glasses.
What are you talking about?
Men aren't attentive
to girls who wear glasses.
Did you ever try it?
No.
- You brought them with you, didn't you?
- Yes.
Then, why don't you put them on?
Find out for yourself.
With you?
Why not?
Well.
If you're worried about me, I'll tell
you right now before you put them on,
I already think
you're quite a strudel.
- Honestly?
- Absolutely.
I've thought so
from the first minute I saw you.
Well, if you really think so.
Go ahead.
Put them on.
- You're crazy.
- No?
- You look better with them on.
- I do?
Gives your face a certain, uh, mystery.
No kidding.
And distinction.
A certain kind of distinction.
Well, what do you know
about that?
You're already a very good-looking girl,
if you don't mind my saying so.
- No, not at all.
- And the glasses.
That particular type gives your face
a very interesting,
uh, difference.
You don't think they make me
look like an old maid.
I've never seen anybody in my whole life
who reminded me less of an old maid.
What's your name?
So what happened was this.
I sent this check to this fellow,
this tax expert.
Instead of paying the tax, he cashed the
check and put the money in his pocket.
But why didn't you tell that
to the government?
Well, I did, but you know
how the government is.
Couldn't be more sympathetic,
but they still wanted the dough.
Even after you told them
that fellow was a crook?
What did that mean? As far as they
were concerned, the only crook was me.
I had to have some proof. That's why
I had to get back and get this check.
Well, how do you like that?
When I found out he'd gone
to Kansas City, I jumped on a plane.
He's either going to kick in with the
money, or I'm going to break his neck.
Is that where he is, Kansas City?
So I understand.
Why are you going
to Atlantic City?
Who's going
Doesn't this plane
go to Atlantic City?
What are you talking about?
This is the Midland Sky Chief.
- Are you kidding?
- Of course not.
We should be in Kansas City
in about, uh, 20 minutes.
Why?
Oh, nothing.
Just one of those things.
Go on.
Tell me some more.
Tell me anything.
Does your family
live there with you?
Oh, no, they couldn't do that.
I see. You mean they have
a place of their own.
Oh, sure, over at Dexter Mills.
I saw a picture
in Harper's Bazaar once,
what they call
a mountain shack.
It was creamy.
Well, here we are.
- Here we are where?
- The shack. This is it.
Well, what do you mean?
This is a shack.
Well, of course.
What did I tell you?
It's very comfortable inside.
Come on.
Just a minute.
Is this really on the level?
- Is what on the level?
- Well, is this really your home?
Well, it is when I'm on duty.
What did you expect?
Well, certainly not this.
I don't know what you mean, honey.
It's just a forestry lookout station.
But they're all pretty much alike.
But if you're so rich, why couldn't
you build yourself a bigger one?
- Like in Harper's Bazaar.
- Rich? Who's rich?
- Aren't you?
- Well, that's a good one.
Where on earth
did you get that idea?
But all these trees.
Didn't you say they were yours?
Well, mine to watch, sure.
That's part of my job.
I don't even own a bush.
Oh. But I thought...
Oh, darling, this is the worst.
What's the matter, sweetheart?
I don't get it.
I'm so crazy about you.
Well, that's wonderful.
I'm crazy about you too.
But I... Oh, honey.
Oh, I see.
What you mean is you're not interested
in a man without trees.
That's not it at all.
I'm crazy about you, but I...
Let's not talk about it.
Do you mind?
If only you'd told me.
I told you. I told you
the first day we went skiing.
I told you then
that's what I was, a ranger.
Is that what you meant?
What else could I have meant?
I'm sorry. I just thought
you meant you came from Texas.
What's the matter
with your dad this time?
He went to another
Republican rally.
Maybe he'd better
join the Democrats.
Not in Maine.
Too lonely.
Can we rent a car
in Portland?
I suppose so.
You mean we're going to
drive back to New York?
It'll probably be pretty expensive,
but I think it's the safest way
not to be seen by anybody.
When you got the measles,
I wouldn't have given ten cents
for my chances of getting
out of this jam without being caught.
- You know what I did?
- What?
I got on long distance with a few
friends around Chicago and St. Louis.
I had them keep sending telegrams
to my wife, signed with my name.
All about this unexpected
business trip I was on.
It worked like a charm.
That sounds very intelligent.
I don't like to boast, but if I hadn't
had that little stroke of brilliance,
there could have been a lot
of very serious results in my home.
And business too.
What are you going to do
to show you're grateful?
- What do you mean?
- Whenever a person pulls a rock
and skins out of it,
they oughta do something nice
for the injured party,
don't you think?
- For instance?
- Well, for one thing,
you ought to drop into Cartier's
tomorrow morning and get your wife
some sort of little bubble
for her wrist.
How about some nice flowers?
Is that all the grateful you are,
five dollars worth of geraniums?
Look, if I gave Mrs. Brewster
a piece of jewelry not on her birthday,
she'd have 25 private detectives
on my tail within 10 minutes.
Well, if you'll pardon my frankness,
I'd be ashamed to admit it.
- I'll send her a nice box of roses.
- She'll love that.
She's not used to
expensive gifts.
Anything more than flowers
would upset her terribly.
All right, then. How about doing
something nice for your daughter?
- What?
- Why don't you inherit her again?
I'm sorry, that's quite
out of the question.
But that wouldn't cost you
anything until you were dead.
I'd rather not discuss it
if you don't mind.
What's the matter with you, anyway?
Everybody loves their children.
Even monkeys. It's a well-known law
of Mother Nature.
Mother Nature never
had to deal with a gigolo.
And what else pray
were you trying to be?
The differences between the two
should be quite obvious, even to you.
And would you be so kindly
as to specify how?
If you don't mind, I don't think
I care to debate the question with you.
Once you get one foot on the ground,
you're really quite a jerk, aren't you?
Where are we now?
We'll be crossing
the George Washington Bridge...
George Washington Bridge?
What are we doing way over there?
On the customary routes,
I could be recognized a dozen times.
This side of the river
no one knows me.
It's just another example of the use
of intelligence in a situation like this.
If you've got intelligence,
you don't need luck.
If you've got that good old American
know-how, you don't need anything else.
Because the simple truth is
that when the chips are really down,
man is still the master
of his own fate.
- The captain of his destiny.
-[ Sirens Wailing]
- What is it?
- Motorcycle cops.
Are you sure
you're not on the lam?
It's all right.
Just keep moving.
I'm awfully sorry
if I'm going too fast.
You're all right.
Just follow me.
Good afternoon, sir.
This is George Washington Bridge Week.
And the city of New York extends
its heartiest congratulations
to the happy couple driving the 50
millionth car across our noble edifice.
-[ Man ] Hold it. This way, lady.
- Another smile, lady.
Hold it. Hold it.
I'm sorry I can't give you
any more, Mrs. Page, but, uh,
you know what the market
is these days.
- Gesundheit.
- Thank you again, Mrs. Page.
[Phone Rings 1
- Hello?
- Miss Page?
Oh, it's you again.
- Are you good for seconds?
- Oh, sure.
- Let's order them now.
- Two more, Mac. Well-done.
And slap a little chili on that one.
- You know what the trouble with you is?
- Which one?
Trouble with you is you're a hamburger
with onions dame and won't admit it.
I wonder how long it took you
to work that one out.
My guess is that I know you
better than you know yourself.
Ketchup.
Uh, coleslaw?
If I can get it on here.
I just don't believe that you're the
kind of girl you pretend to be at all.
I'll say this for you, that's
quite a line you've got there.
Here. Pickles?
Thanks.
It's all an act. You know as well
as I do that money isn't everything.
Who told you it wasn't?
Nobody had to.
Did you ever have any?
A little, yes.
Then, how do you know
it isn't everything?
Do you seriously believe having money
automatically brings you happiness?
Well, no, but it doesn't
automatically depress me either.
I don't believe you, Schatze.
Look, Tommy, I'm in a jam here
Don't you understand?
I'm in a very bad
financial situation.
If those kids don't come back,
I'm on the hook for a year's
rent for that apartment.
So, what do you think
I should do now,
fall in love with a character
who doesn't even own a necktie?
- Haven't they written to you?
- How can they? They're illiterate.
- Listen, honey...
- It's no use, Tommy boy.
Just as soon as I finish this horse
burger, I never want to see you again.
[Ring]
Hello?
How about taking a look
at Miss Liberty today?
Well.
[ Boat Horn Blows]
If you were solvent, it would be
an entirely different matter.
But I had it with a grease monkey
like you, and that's all I want of that.
Okay, Miss Cafe Society, take a look out
there and give me a rest for a moment.
And the truth of the matter,
I don't care what you say,
is that if you're not loaded,
you've already got two strikes on you.
I already said okay. What else
do you want me to say about it?
As soon as we get off this barge,
I never want to see you again.
[Phone Rings 1
- Yes?
-Tonight?
No.
I mean it I tell you.
Just as soon as we get home,
I never want to see...
I'm sorry we can't give you
any more, Mrs. Page.
I already laughed at that one.
Well, anyway, thanks again.
May I come in?
May I change my mind?
Is this on the level?
From the bottom of my heart.
Then, hold it
for just one second.
Fred? Fred?
This is Mrs. Page.
Grab that furniture man and tell him
to bring that stuff right back up here.
Do you understand?
Don't even move.
Well?
Yes.
[ Piano]
ls something wrong,
Mrs. Page?
I don't know.
I just feel so lonely.
- Your friends?
- Yeah.
Not one of those two dingbats
to stand up with me.
Well, there's still a good hope
they may come yet.
If they come now,
I'll throw them out on their necks.
- But I thought...
- I wanted them yesterday.
What time have I got
to laugh at them now?
Well, for crying out loud, a party.
Wait a minute.
- There's Loco!
- Well, hi!
- What is it?
- Schatze's wedding. Didn't you know?
- Who to?
- Dallas, Texas.
Wow!
- Pardon me, but my name is Ding Dong.
- How do you do?
- Did you have much trouble?
- What do you mean, trouble?
He's absolutely insane
about me.
- No kidding.
- Out of his mind.
- Do you know how much he's worth?
- How much?
- Thirty mil.
- He's not.
Give or take a mil.
Oh, isn't
that wonderful?
Oh, and he's a doll.
A perfect doll.
- What a break.
- I'm not kidding. It's a dream marriage.
What about you?
Where have you been all this time?
Oh, I went back
to Maine.
What do you mean,
you went back to Maine?
Well, to tell you the truth,
I got married up there.
Not to that Shriner.
- Oh, no, he was already married.
- That's what I thought.
Who'd you marry?
Well, he's not anybody
in particular.
Just a fella
I met up there.
But I'm absolutely
crazy about him.
How do you like that?
Both of us at the same time.
What does he do?
- He's a ranger.
- Cattle, you mean?
No, he's a forest ranger.
Well, that's not bad. If you get enough
trees, they're really worth something.
- How'd you meet him?
- I don't mean he owns them,
he just watches them.
You mean,
just looks at them?
He's got a house on top of a mountain.
They keep a lookout for fires
so all those trees
don't burn down.
How can he make any dough
out of that?
He doesn't, much.
You mean
he's a kind of fireman?
That's it.
- Thank you.
- Mr. Hanley?
- You have the license, I suppose.
- Yes, right here.
Wouldn't you
like to meet him?
Oh, sure.
Is he here?
I'll get him.
[ Piano]
Hiya, Schatze.
Well, I'll be
a monkey's uncle.
Congratulations, honey. We read about it
on the plane. I think it's just creamy.
You know how much
he's got?
- How much?
- Fifty mil.
- Brother!
- Give or take a mil.
Have you been
shopping yet?
When they open the doors,
I fall in.
- What a break!
- Where have you been?
- Kansas City.
- For what?
That's where Freddie and I
got married.
- You mean you married that crowbar?
- Well, yes.
Honest to goodness, Pola,
you need a governess.
I could have pegged that guy as a phony
when I was eight years old.
Oh, not Stewart.
I married Freddie.
Freddie? Who he?
Well, it's a little mixed up. You see,
I got on his plane to Kansas City.
I thought you were going
to Atlantic City.
I was, but the first stop
for this plane was Kansas City.
Never mind. I don't want to
hear any more about it.
Just tell me one thing...
is he holding or not?
Well, yes and no.
Oh, no, no, no.
Not you too.
I mean, he'd be holding
if he could get his hands on it.
- Say that again.
- Well, he's on the lam.
- A thief?
- No, no, he's not a thief.
As a matter of fact,
he owns this apartment.
But he gave this guy a check
for his income tax...
Then, what's
he on the lam for?
Then, he went up to break this
guy's neck, but his glasses fell off.
- Whose glasses?
- Freddie's.
And the guy nearly
broke his neck.
You mean, he's blind too?
Blinder than me.
Here he is.
This is Schatze, darling.
Oh, congratulations,
Mrs. Page.
Thank you. Congratulations to you too.
She's okay.
- I think so.
- And this is Pola.
- Glad to meet you.
- Holy Toledo!
- Isn't he cute?
- Just a minute.
Two more pounds
and she could be arrested for bigamy.
Pardon me, Mrs. Page. Mr. Hanley would
like to know if there's a maid of honor.
- If he can find one.
- Can I be it?
Matron, I believe, is about
the best you can hope for.
- Shall I tell him?
- Take him.
- Come on, before Pola gets here.
- Bye.
Bye.
It's just Schatze.
Come on.
- Here he is.
- Hi, Mrs. Page.
- Is that going to be permanent?
- No, it's just a brace.
He takes it off
at night.
Don't you worry.
I'm going to get even with him yet.
I just have to lay
a little low for a while.
We're going underground
right after the ceremony.
- You don't mind?
- Love it
Well, congratulations
to you too.
I think we'd better get started. Some
of the kids are beginning to foam over.
Okay, tell them to blow the whistle.
You're still sure?
Of course.
[ Piano:
"The Wedding March” ]
"Dearly beloved,
we are gathered together here..."
- Please.
- What's the matter, dear?
My ankle.
Can you take me back?
Why, yes. Of course.
[Murmuring]
[ Piano]
You're just too nice a guy
to get married to someone
that doesn't love you all out.
Was that what it was?
What else?
I can think of
a number of reasons
why you should never have
considered me in the first place.
Have I hurt you
very bad?
You have.
But I'll recover.
You sound as though
as you already have.
No. No, that's just one of
the few advantages of age
Disappointments become
a normal part of life.
But what do you think
I should tell the guests?
Oh, just tell them Mrs. Page
has blown her stack at last.
No one will give you
an argument on it.
Wouldn't you like to talk it over
first with Loke and Pola?
- Those bubbleheads.
- Why do you say that?
Did you see what those
two goofballs turned up with?
Yeah, I saw
Loke's forest ranger.
A fireman for trees.
Seemed like
a very nice boy.
- Did you see what Pola brought back?
- No.
- A fugitive from justice.
And a blind one at that.
Young man?
As far as I could tell,
in back of that Halloween getup.
Well, they love them,
don't they?
Drooling,
all four of them.
And who is
your young man?
- What young man?
- The one you're in love with.
Who said I was in love
with a young man?
I did.
Well,
it's a sin and a shame,
but I guess I've got to admit it.
I am.
- Who is he?
- What does that matter?
Well, I don't think it's unnatural
that I should have some curiosity.
He's nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
A character straight
from Characterville.
- Is that his name?
- Brookman.
- Brookman what?
- Tom Brookman.
You say he's non-holding?
One more hamburger
would break him.
What does he do?
He won't say, but that's nothing to me.
I already know.
- What?
- He's a gas pump jockey.
How do you know?
How do I know
how I know?
There's something about those guys
that I can spot every time I see them.
I married one once,
remember?
Does he
really love you?
To hear him tell it,
he does.
Well, what's to stop you
from marrying him?
Nothing now, but it's scarcely
what you'd call progress.
- He's here now, you know.
- Where?
- Out there.
- How do you know?
Well, there's a character out there
who looks like a gas pump jockey to me.
- Has he got on a tie?
- No, no tie.
And at a formal ceremony.
You see what I mean?
[ Speaking Latin ]
Well, you can certainly
say that again.
And after I told him
I never wanted to see him again, ever.
Who does he think he is, anyway?
Crashing my wedding.
Well, suppose I ask him?
Now just a minute, J.D.
Hiya, Tom.
Okay, I guess.
Congratulations.
- Congratulations to you.
- Don't be funny.
- Still the character, huh?
- Well, why not?
All she talks about is dough,
dough, dough. Nothing but dough.
So, if that's all she wants, you can
have her. I don't want any part of her.
That's the way she talks, of course,
but that's not the way she feels.
I'll bet.
What happened?
It was a delayed decision
in your favor.
- Are you kidding?
- Not in the least.
- Did you tell her about me?
- Of course not.
So far as she knows,
you're still hustling a gas pump.
I don't believe this.
- All right. Let's go ask her.
- Wait a minute.
Wait a minute, J.D.
You think I ought to tell her now?
Are you crazy?
She obviously likes gas pump jockeys
better than millionaires.
What do you want to do,
disillusion the girl?
Mr. Brookman, darling.
- Well, you've got a crust.
- Just a minute.
- A big wedding and you with no necktie.
- Listen to me.
Everybody else here dressed up in
striped pants and you show up like a...
- Listen, Schatze!
- I never want to see you again.
Hey, hey, hey, what about
a cheese dog burger this time, huh?
[ Several People
Talking At Once]
Following the ceremony, the party
adjourned to a fashionable greasy spoon,
where perfectly delicious
dog burgers were served.
What happened with those zillionaires
everybody was talking about?
Oh, what always happens
to rich zillionaires.
I've got nothing to worry about.
What did you tell me you were worth?
Oh, I should say
in the neighborhood of 14 dollars,
-give or take a nickel.
- That's all cash too.
How about you, Killer?
How are you fixed?
To tell you the truth,
if I can get my hands on it...
You're fixed but good.
I can tell.
Wait a minute. I want to hear
from Mr. Fill 'Er Up.
Just what you estimate
your fortune at?
Oh, about 200 million,
I should imagine.
Oh, that's not enough.
Might that all be in cash?
I could probably dig up
a couple million cash if I had to.
Oh, that's wonderful.
What might the rest be in, oil?
- Some oil.
- Uh-huh.
- Some airline stock.
- Good.
A little steel.
Some cattle down in Texas.
Couple of coal mines in Alabama.
Bit of real estate here and there.
Some automobile stocks.
The Brookman Building.
And, of course,
Brookman, Pennsylvania.
A whole city he owns yet. Wouldn't
you know that would happen to me?
Give me the check, Mac.
[All Talking At Once]
Keep the change, Mac.
[ Glass Breaks]
Gentlemen,
to our wives.
[Music Playing ]
English - US - SDH